<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Sample Document Title</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p/>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc sameAs="http://www.cwrc.ca">
				<p>Created from original research by members of CWRC/CSÉC unless
					otherwise noted.</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>Deposicions of Witnesses on the Complainant’s part.</head>
				<p>//C</p><p>//IMG_0409 and IMG_0412//<lb/>
 Deposic<expan>i</expan>ons of Witnesses had and taken the Twelfth day of October in the Ninth Yeare of the Reigne of our Soveraigne Lady Anne by the Grace of God of Great Brittain France and Ireland<lb/>
 Queen Defender of the Faith &amp;c Anno D<expan>o</expan>m<expan>in</expan>i 1710 at the Dwelling house of Mary Twitt Widow comonly called or known by the name of Row<unclear>man</unclear> Passage House scituate lyeing and being in the Parish of Clifton in the<lb/>
 County of Gloucester before Thomas Walter Esq<expan>ui</expan>re Rowland Thrupp Thomas Oldfeild and Samuel Fox Gent<expan>leman</expan> By Virtue of a Comic<expan>i</expan>on <unclear>ifsned</unclear> out of her Maj<expan>es</expan>ties High Court of Chancery to them direcc<expan>i</expan>on <unclear>for &amp; xxxxxx</unclear><lb/>
 of Witnesses in a certaine Cause there depending Betweene Forest Ashfeild Gent<expan>leman</expan> Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick Barr<expan>one</expan>t Def<expan>endan</expan>t on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part as followeth.<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Elizabeth Cox Wife of John Cox of the Citty of Bristoll Tobacconist aged Five and Thirty Yeares of there abouts Sworne and examined on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
 12.) To the Twelfthe Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y <add>this Deponent</add> Saith That about Ten dayes after the decease of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother She this Depon<expan>en</expan>t went with Mrs Mary Ashfeild the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Sister as a Companion to the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts Mr Edwards in Bristoll in order for the said Mrs. Ashfeild to discourse him about what the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother <unclear>left to?</unclear><lb/>
 the said Mrs Ashfeild by her Will And the said Mr Edwards then Declared to this Depon<expan>enen</expan>t and the said Mrs Ashfeild that he beleived or thought that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not design the Will the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother made should stand as her Will, but that it was made onely to fright her <unclear>xxxxxxxxxxxxxx</unclear><lb/>
 them in <unclear>and or used</unclear> words very much to that effect. </p>
 <p>
 William Leman of Wrington in the County of Somersett Yeoman aged Forty Yeares or thereabouts Sworne and examined on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
 29.) To the Nine and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That about Two Yeares Since to the best of this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts remembrance the Def<expan>endan</expan>t Mr Edwards gave this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t <add>as</add> a Sheriffes Bayliffe for the County of Somersett a Writt against the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t at the suite of the Def<expan>endan</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodricke <unclear>xxxxxxx this</unclear><lb/>
 Depon<expan>en</expan>t arrested the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t who gave an appearance to the same but whether the same was charged for Twenty Thousand pounds or any other and what Sum<expan>m</expan>e this Depon<expan>en</expan>t can not remember but before this Depon<expan>en</expan>t arrested the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t he had orders from the said Mr Edwards not to <unclear>insist on xxxx</unclear><lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Alice Humphrey of Tickenham in the County of Somersett Spinster already Sworne and examined on the Defend<expan>an</expan>ts part and now on the pl<expan>ain</expan>t<expan>iff</expan>s part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
 17.) To the Seventeenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That Elianor Glanville this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts late Mistress deceased did for every Yeare during the time this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived with her both in Winter and Summer catch flies and butterflyes and putt them into boxes to carry to London as she told <unclear>them</unclear><lb/>
 and the rest of her servants and called such flies and butterflies by particular Names but what those partiular Names were this Depon<expan>en</expan>t cannot remember.<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Mary Ashfeild of Tickenham aforesaid Spinster aged Thirty Yeares and upwards Sworne and examined Deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
 1.) To the First Interr<expan>ogatorr</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That she hath known the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t who is her brother from his infancy to this time but hath not known the Def<expan>endan</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick for more than Fifteen Months past.<lb/>
 3.) To the Third Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That Mrs Eleanor Glanvile the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts and this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Mother had Seven Children by her two husbandds Mr. Edmund Ashfeild dec<expan>eas</expan>ed and Mr Richard Glanvile (vizt.) Katherine Ashfeild dec<expan>eas</expan>ed the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and <unclear>this</unclear> Dep<expan>onen</expan>t by the said Mr<lb/>
 Ashfeild and Richard Glanvile and Elianor Glanvile both now living and James glanvile and another daughter whose name this Depon<expan>en</expan>t cannot remember who both dyed in ther Infancy by the said Mr Glanvile and Saith That in or about the Month of July One thousand Six hundred <unclear>obscured...</unclear><lb/>
 and Five as neare as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t can remember the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was about Eight and Twenty Yeares of Age this Depon<expan>en</expan>t about Six and Twenty Yeares of Age and the said Richard Glanvile <add>this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts brother in law </add>about Seventeen Yeares and the said Elinor Glanvile about Sixteen Yeares of Age and that She this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
 and the said Richard and Eleanor Glanvile her brother and Sister were then of the Roman Catholick Religion but the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t then p<expan>ro</expan>fessed himself to be and still is of the protestant Religion And this depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that since that time She hath also Embraced and now is of the true Protestant Religion<lb/>
 but her said brother and sister Glanvile continue to be Roman Chatholicks And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further saith That this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother Mrs. Eleanor Glanvile p<expan>ro</expan>fessed herself alwayes to be of the Romish Religion and as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleives dyed so.<lb/>
 4.) To the Fourth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That in her Opinion and Judgement she and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t alwayes behaved themselves towards their said Mother with duty and respect <add>and</add> that they did not dare to do otherwise their said Mother keeping them continually in greate Awe and <unclear>Subsecc<expan>i</expan>on</unclear> and th<unclear>en on</unclear><lb/>
 herself on all occasions a very Severe Mother and about Six or Seven Yeares Since the said Mrs Glanvile sent this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t from London to Tickenham in the County of Somersett to look after her affairs there And this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t staid there about Four Months and behaved herself so well in that time that the Neighbours<lb/>
 took notice of her Management and said they thought she managed much better than her Mother and at the End of Four Months her said Mother came down to Tickenham aforesaid without sending any notice of comeing to this Depon<expan>an</expan>t or her servants and as soon as She came within the <unclear>grass</unclear> of her house this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
 asked her to give her blessing which she did and <add>a little</add> after fell into a violent passion with this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and called her ill names and bid her goe out of the house and threw severall things at her head and made her leave the house and ly that night at a Neighbours though this Depon<expan>en</expan>t did not give her the least p<expan>ro</expan>vocac<expan>i</expan>on<lb/>
 so to do And she further saith that she was a cruel and hard Mother to all her Children And this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t saith <expan>tha</expan>t their Mother bestowed little or no Educac<expan>i</expan>on on them only she putt this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t to a boarding school at Hammersmith where she suffered her to stay but for Four Months and that <add>was</add>the greatest part of her<lb/>
 school learning and Educac<expan>i</expan>on And her Brother the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was putt to one Mr Burges whom was formerly parson of the parish of Tickenham and afterwards Turn'd Roman Catholick and taught School in London with whom he continued for some time but how long this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t doth not remember And this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t<lb/>
 Saith that as a farther instance of her Mothers Severity to her she putt this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t a Servant to Mrs Pridgett in St. James's London where she was to have such Wages as her Mistress would give her and staid there almost One Quarter of a Yeare and then her Mother removed her thence and putt her to an Embroiderer<lb/>
 where her Mother paid some Weekes for her being and afterwards left her to work for her livelyhood and Maintenance, then this Depon<expan>en</expan>t was sent from London to Tickenham to manage her affairs there as aforesaid and afterwards her said Mother Turn'd this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t quite out of Doors but at night without her Mothers<lb/>
 knowledge She gott into her Mothers house and lay there, though at the same time her said Mother ordered her Servants to deny this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t Victuals and drink if she should come in to her house while her said Mother was at Bristoll whither She was then goeing and ordered her Servants that this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t should have nothing<lb/>
 but bear Walls And this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t beleives she had actually starved had other Mothers Serv<expan>an</expan>ts and the Neighbours Supported her, after this when her said Mother came from Bristoll she putt this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t a Covenant Servant to the Lady Hamilton in Bristoll for the wages of Forty Shillings p<expan>er</expan> Ann<expan>u</expan>m where<lb/>
 she lived about Ten Months and left her Service being sick and then this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t workt with a Sempstress for Six Weekes where she lay sick some time and was releived by her Friends in the said Citty of Bristoll and many other Hardshipps this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t hath undergone by reason of their said<lb/>
 Mothers disaffection Severity and unkindness to them.<lb/>
 5.) To the Fifth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t had not to this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts knowledge any allowance from his Mother till he was Twenty Yeares of age onely his Mother paid for his boarding Schooling and maintenance And that after he was Twenty Yeares old his said Mother allowed him after the rate<lb/>
 of Thirty pounds p<expan>er</expan> Ann<expan>u</expan>m for about Twelve Months and after that she gave him no allowance at all for severall Yeares to this Dep<expan>onen</expan>ts knowledge and beleife till compelled by this Hono<expan>ura</expan>ble Court to allow him Eight Shillings p<expan>er</expan> Week for his subsistance and says that she does not know that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t spent any<lb/>
 Sum<expan>m</expan>e of money or contracted any Debts to any Value and if he has run in debt his Mother gave out She would not pay it neither was he any wayes extravagant in his life or convercac<expan>i</expan>on otherwise That he would sometimes take a cheerfull cupp. <lb/>
 7. &amp; 8.) To the seventh and Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>ys this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that in this Dep<expan>onen</expan>ts Judgem<expan>en</expan>t and opinion her Mother was not a discreet Woman in the Managem<expan>en</expan>t of her affairs nor so reckoned amongst her Neighbours and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t doth not beleive that her said Mother was alwayes of Sound Mind and understanding<lb/>
 but that she was oftentimes very whimsicall insomuch that she was uncapable of manageing her Estate and Children for she often times Turned away good Tennants from her Estate and lett the same run to ruine for want of Managem<expan>en</expan>t and husbandry.<lb/>
 9.) To the Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Mother did Manage the house wherein she lived very meanly not having or keeping things necessary or covenient for her house of Family and she was many Yeares before her death unsettled for this Depon<expan>en</expan>t remembers that she removed herself from<lb/>
 house to house from family to family Nine times within the Space of one Yeare and an half but the reason why she removed herself so often as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleives was because she was troubled with dreams Fancyes and whimsies And saith that for neare Seaven Yeares before her said Mother died she kept<lb/>
 onely two parish Girles or apprentices as her constant Servants but Sometimes she hired other persons for a Quarter of a Yeare or there abouts.<lb/>
 12.) To the Twelfth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y She saith That within a fortnight after this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Mother died this Depon<expan>en</expan>t with one Mrs Cocks went to the Def<expan>endan</expan>t Thomas Edwards house in Bristoll to enquire of him how her Mother left her affaires who told her the purport or effect of her Mothers Will and said that he beleived that<lb/>
 her Mother when she made the Will did not intend that it Should stand but did it onely to keep her Children in Awe or Words to that effect upon which Mrs Cox said that she thought 'twas unjust in her Mother to leave her Estate from her children to a Stranger and thereupon the said Mr Edwards replied that he thought by the<lb/>
 Management of her Estate she had sometimes Whimsies or Maggotts or words to that purport.<lb/>
 17.) To the Seventeenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that her said Mother had Spent a great deale of money in Employing most of the Girls and other p<expan>er</expan>sons in the Parish of Tickenham for severall Yeares to take and catch butterflies flies and worms and when she had them she would putt them into papers some of which papers<lb/>
 she would call boxes and other dripping pans and saith that her said Mother would often send or carry them to London and that She there Rented a Room on purpose to keep them And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath by her Mothers order paid Eight Shillings in a day to poor Girls and <unclear>xx</unclear> her persons for catching such Flies <add>and wormes And saith that shee many years delighted &amp; dealt much in such flies</add><lb/>
 and Insects And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further saith that her said Mother had particular Names for above One hundred sort of such Butterflies flies and Worms and that she numbred and named most of them and Entered such Names and Numbers of such Insects in one or more Book or Books she kept for that purpose onely<lb/>
 And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith she beleives her Mother did all this to please her Fancy and also beleives she laid out more money in such Fancies than she bestowed on her Children during the time.<lb/>
//IMG_0415 and IMG_0416 with close ups IMG_0417//<lb/>
 19.) To the Nineteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y She saith That she hath heard her said Mother say that she would disinherit every one of her Children for that they were disobedient to her but when any person ask't her where in they were disobedient or undutifull She could not give any one instance thereof as many of the said persons hath told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t.<lb/>
 21.) To the One and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogato</expan>ry this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That Mr Parrott and Mr Baptist in this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y named are both Romish preists but of what order knoweth not but saith that old Goodman Whale in this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y also named is related in some distance to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts said Mother.<lb/>
 24.) To the Four and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That her said Mother had often had conceits and thoughts that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t did correspond with her husband Mr. Glanvile when at the same time thid Depon<expan>en</expan>t never saw or heard from Mr Glanvile Since his Seperac<expan>i</expan>on from their said Mother and beleives the<lb/>
 Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t did not till after her Mothers death and that they designed to bring her to the said Mr. Glanvile and contrive with him to Murder her or to that effect and hath often heard the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t Speak very dutifully of and to his said Mother when she talk'd to him of anything of that Nature.<lb/>
 25.) To the Five and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts said Mother sent him to France into a Monastry which he left in about Nine Months time because his Mother would not allow him money or support him there and after that she caused the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t to be sent to St. Jermain's where he lived in the house of one Mrs.<lb/>
 Clarke for about One Yeare and half dureing all which time the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts said Mother sent him but one half Guinea and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that there is still due to the said Mrs. Clarke above One hundred pounds for the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts dyet and Maintenance as she beleives.<lb/>
 31.) Tp tje pme amd Thirtieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that neither she nor the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t to her knowledge ever went to see or conversed or held any Correspondence with Mr. Glanvile from the time he seperated from her to her death but beleives that the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts said Mother did dureing that time know that the said Mr.<lb/>
 Glanvile was liveing And saith That the said Mr. Glanvile did not to this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts knowledge come into the Country where the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts said Mother dwelt after such their Sep<expan>er</expan>ac<expan>i</expan>on or that he did attempt to do her any Mischeife after that time.<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 John Pigott at Breckley in the County of Som<expan>er</expan>sett Esq<expan>ui</expan>re aged about Sixty Yeares Sworne and examined on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
 1.) To the First Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That he has known the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t for above 7 Yeares past but doth not know the Def<expan>endan</expan>t.<lb/>
 2.) To the Second Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That he well knoew Eleanor Glanvile the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother and Edmund Ashfeild Esq<expan>ui</expan>re his Father both <unclear>rece<expan>ieve</expan>d</unclear> for above Forty Years past but doth not know any other of the p<expan>er</expan>sons in this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y named And saith that the said Edmund Ashfeild dyed about One and Thirty Yeares<lb/>
 Since, and the said Mrs. Eleanor Glanvile dyed about Two Yeares Since.<lb/>
 7.) To the Seventh Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That for Thirty Yeares past and upwards he lived within Four Miles of Tickenham in the County of Somersett where the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother gen<expan>er</expan>ally inhabited and dwelt and was very intimate and well acquainted with her, And Saith she was in this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Judgem<expan>en</expan>t and opinion very<lb/>
 unquiet in her Mind and not in her perfect Sences for that about the time King William landed first in England there came an order to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t from the Councell as one of the Deputy <unclear>Leiftennts</unclear> &amp; Iustices of Peace for the County of Somersett to search the houses and to take &amp; seize the horses &amp; arms of all papists and <unclear>persons xxxxxx obscured</unclear><lb/>
 such in this Deponents neighbourhood or division and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother being a papist this Depon<expan>en</expan>t went in a freindly manner to her house to search for arms &amp; horses and he desired her to bring all the armes she had which she did and amongst them brought a Bionett to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t &amp; desired him to take that which this Depon<expan>en</expan>t drew out of its<lb/>
 Scabbard and gave to her againe and in taking it she turn'd the point of it to her own breast &amp; desired this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to run it into her saying he would do her a great kindness and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t took it &amp; carried it away (tho' offered to leave it with her) with the rest of the arms and two or three horses and at that time &amp; ever since till she dyed as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
 hath heard <unclear>deid</unclear> all of her Neighbours say she was and hath been out of her Sences and Maggotty.<lb/>
 8.) To the Eight Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother managed her Estate for many yeares past in a very ill and unaccountable manner both in letting and setting the same and not putting any of it into repaire but letting it constantly run to ruine and that at the time of her death most of the Fences belonging to her Estate<lb/>
 downe and lay open and she was not by this Depon<expan>en</expan>t or her Neighbours reckoned a woman fitt to manage her Estate for many yeares before her death.<lb/>
 10. &amp; 17.) To the tenth and Seventeenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That he hath heard from her Neighbours that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother hath severall times <unclear>plaid Frantice Tricks</unclear> and dealt and delighted much in Butterflies Spiders and worms &amp; that she called many of those Insects by the names of Kings and Queens and other such like names that she<lb/>
 <unclear>also</unclear> had a Fancy once to pace a Bull and make a padd for her own riding and had many such like unaccountable whimms and fancies.<lb/>
 13.) To the thirteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That Mr. Ashfeild the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Father about two or three yeares before his death told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t that his wife had settled her Estate upon him which made him take great delight in it saying 'twould be the better for his Family and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t observed the <unclear>said</unclear> Mr. Ashfield afterwards <unclear>to be</unclear><lb/>
 a very good husband upon it and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that he hath heard Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re of Wraxall in the County of Somersett a near Neighbour to the said Mr Ashfeild sev<expan>er</expan>all times in the life time of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother and since the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t turn'd Protestant say and declare That he knew there was a Deed of Settlem<expan>en</expan>t made by the said Mrs Ashfeild<lb/>
 of her Estate on her husband Mr. Ashfeild and that he the said Mr. Gorges had seen it and saith the said Mr Gorges was a Justice of Peace and a Man of very great Integrity and reputac<expan>i</expan>on in his Country and that he dyed about two yeares since.<lb/>
 26.) To the Six and twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That he well knew the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Father Mr Ashfeild before his Interrmarriage with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother that he was a Lymner and lived in very good repute in London &amp; beleives he left the City of London and his business there on his Marriage with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother to live with<lb/>
 her on her Estate at Tickenham and says that he alwayes behav'd himselfe towards his said wife very kind and obliging and that she was exceeding fond of him and expressed herselfe very respectfull and kind to him and <add>that</add> they lived very comfortably together and saith that he hath heard Mrs. Ashfeild say she came from London to live in the Country<lb/>
 because she would have as much of Mr. Ashfeilds Company as she could or to that Effect.<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Robert Brown of Nailesey in the County of Somersett Horse pacer aged forty seven yeares sworne and examined on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
 7. &amp; 17.) To the Seventh and Seventeenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes This Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That he hath lived within one Mile of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother for most part of his lifetime and hath known her soe long and says That in his this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Judgem<expan>en</expan>t She was not right in her sences Some times and he hath heard the Neighbours often times say as much And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further Saith<lb/>
 that about Seven Yeares Since the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother sent for this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to her house in Tickenham in ord<expan>er</expan> to pace a Mare of hers and when this Depon<expan>en</expan>t came to her house he found her danceing and singing and in a very merry Mood This Depon<expan>en</expan>t told her he was come to pace her Mare, she answered this Depon<expan>en</expan>t she would give him Ten Shillings<lb/>
 to pace her Mare, but she and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t did not agree and as he was goeing about his business she called him back again and told him she had a Bull which she would him pace for her this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t told her such a thing could not be done, but she said she would have it done to please her fancy on which this Depon<expan>en</expan>t we<unclear>nt his</unclear> way And sa<unclear>ys</unclear><lb/>
 That by her Wayes and her dealings She was not a sensible Woman and was very Maggotty.<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Mary Keene Wife of James Keene of Tickenham in the Country of Glouc<expan>estershi</expan>re Husbandman aged Thirty Yeares and upwards Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part Deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
 7.) To the Seventh Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y She Saith that she lived very near the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother Mrs Elianor Glanvile for Ten Yeares or thereabouts and was well acquainted with her and lived with her as a Servant for Seven Weekes or thereabouts about Five Yeares and an half agoe as near as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t now remembers and after she<lb/>
 left the said Mrs Glanvile she lived as a Servant with one John Bruton in the Same house at Tickenham Court where Mrs Glanvile then also dwelt And saith that she was not reputed by her Neighbours a Wise or discreet Woman or of Sound understanding but was often very fickle minded and Maggotty.<lb/>
 8th.) To the Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not Manage her Estate like a Woman of discretion nor of Sound understanding and Saith that she would often lett her Land or Estate to Strangers at <unclear>a great</unclear> Rent who often run away in her Debt or paid her nothing rather then lett it to her Neighbours who would <add>have paid her her Rent</add><lb/>
 10.) To the Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That while she lived w<expan>i</expan>th John Bruton named in her deposic<expan>i</expan>on to the Seventh Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother about Twelve and one of the Clock one Night Alarm'd this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and the rest of the said J<expan>oh</expan>n Brutons Family then being in bed in the said house pr<expan>e</expan>tending that there were Theives in or about the<lb/>
 house And that thereupon this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and two of her Fellow Servants gott up and Search't the house very diligently but found no body there besides their own Family.<lb/>
 17.) To the Seventeenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did for severall Yeares before her death collect and buy severall Sorts of Flyes, Butterflyes and Wormes and kept them in Severall Boxes and gave Names to severall sorts of them but what such names were this Depon<expan>en</expan>t cannot remember And that she did Imploy<lb/>
 severall persons to collect and gather such flyes and Worms for which the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother paid severall times six pence at a time to each person for one Fly or Worm and sometimes less or more according to her Fancy.<lb/>
 20.) To the Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That she beleives the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did really Value her Blind Bitch and her Butterflyes more than her Children.<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Robert Churchouse of Clapton in the County of Somersett Yeoman aged Fifty and Nine Yeares or thereabouts (being a professed Quaker and haveing made his <unclear>solem pass xxxxxxxxxx</unclear>on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part declareth as followeth.<lb/>
 19.) To the Nineteenth Interr<expan>ogtor</expan>y this Declarant Saith That about a Yeare agoe he was in company of one Matthew Knight late of Tickenham in the County of Somersett Husbandman who formerly work't for or was a Servant to Mrs. Eleanor Glanvile the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother and the said Matthew Knight then told this Declarant That when he was<lb/>
 carrying the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother to Bristoll whe<unclear>n</unclear> she was subpeona'd to London by her Son the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother told him it was the worst thing that ever <unclear>Man</unclear> had done (being a Name She often called the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t by <add>And</add> That she was goeing to Bristoll to make her Will and she intended to give all her Estate from the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t to the Defend<expan>en</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r<lb/>
 Henry Goodrick And that he the said Matthew Knight thereupon askt her why she would give her Estate from her Children To which the said Mrs Glanvile replied that she had no Child but her <unclear>Nurse xcozen'd</unclear> her and gave her Changelings or used words to the very same effect And saith that the said Matthew Knight died half a Yeare agoe or the<unclear>reabouts</unclear><lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 <unclear>4 signatures, can't make out 2</unclear><lb/>
 Thomas Walter<lb/>
 Rowland Thrupp<lb/>
 Tho<expan>mas</expan> Oldfeild<lb/>
 Sam<expan>ue</expan>l Fox<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 //Verso//<lb/>
 Depo<expan>si</expan>t<expan>i</expan>ons<lb/>
 Ashfeild v<lb/>
 Goodrick bar<expan>onent</expan><lb/>
 </p></div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>