<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Sample Document Title</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p/>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc sameAs="http://www.cwrc.ca">
				<p>Created from original research by members of CWRC/CSÉC unless
					otherwise noted.</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>Schedule of Defendant.</head>
				<p>//IMG_0315 and IMG_0316//
</p>
<p>
 The Schedule whereto the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts Answer referrs<lb/>
 </p>
<p>
 25 Novembris<lb/>
 <unclear>x Jambe 2d</unclear>:}<lb/>
 Imprimis One Indenture Tripartite of that date made Between Elianor Ashfeild of the first part Richard<lb/>
 Glanville of the second part and Edward Gorges and W<expan>illia</expan>m Rogers of the third part (reciting two Indentures<lb/>
 of Lease and release bearing date the twenty third and twenty fourth of that instant November made by<lb/>
 the said Elianor Ashfeild to the said Edward Gorges and William Rogers of all her Mannors Lands<lb/>
 and hereditaments in the County of Somersett And reciting a marriage intended to be had Between<lb/>
 the said Rich<expan>ar</expan>d Glanville and Elianor Ashfeild being a Deed declaring the Trusts on which the<lb/>
 <unclear>they recited</unclear> Indentures were made<lb/>
<unclear>February</unclear> 1686}<lb/>
 Item One Indenture of that date made Between the said Richard Glanville and Elianor his wife<lb/>
 Edward Gorges and William Rogers of the one part and S<expan>i</expan>r Dudley North K<expan>nigh</expan>t of the other parte purporting<lb/>
 the Counterpart of an Addic<expan>i</expan>onall Security to S<expan>i</expan>r Dudley North and Lady Anne his wife for three hundred<lb/>
 pounds and Interest.<lb/>
9 December 1693}<lb/>
 Item One Indenture of that date made Between Elianor Glanville then wife of the said Richard<lb/>
 Glanville and the said Edward Gorges and William Rogers of the one part and S<expan>i</expan>r William Merrick K<expan>nigh</expan>t<lb/>
 of the other part purporting the Counterpart of an Addic<expan>i</expan>onall Security to S<expan>i</expan>r William Merrick for Twelve<lb/>
 hundred and Fifty pounds and Interest.<lb/>
3 September 1694}<lb/>
 Item One Ind<expan>entu</expan>re Tripartite of that date made between the same Partys purporting to the Counterpart of<lb/>
 a Security to S<expan>i</expan>r William Merrick for one thousand Four hundred <add>and fifty</add> pounds and Interest.<lb/>
12 January 1696}<lb/>
 One Ind<expan>entu</expan>re Tripartite of that date made Between the same partys purporting the Counterp<expan>ar</expan>ts<lb/>
 of Security to S<expan>i</expan>r William Merrick for one then said Seaven hundred pounds and Interest<lb/>
25 January 1698}<lb/>
 Item one other Ind<expan>entu</expan>re of that date purporting <expan>th</expan>e Counterpart of a mortgage of Backwell Parke<lb/>
 for securing Eight hundred pounds and Interest<lb/>
19 September 1704<lb/>
 Item one Ind<expan>entu</expan>re Tripartite of that date made Between the said Elianor Glanville of the first part<lb/>
 Edward Gorges and William Rogers of the second part and John Shipton of the third part purporting<lb/>
 the Counterpart of a Lease to John Shipton of certain Lands at Tickenham To hold for three years<lb/>
 and afterwards for four years if he and the said Elianor did agree at and under the yearly rend of<lb/>
 forty six pounds.<lb/>
</p></div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
