<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Sample Document Title</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p/>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc sameAs="http://www.cwrc.ca">
				<p>Created from original research by members of CWRC/CSÉC unless
					otherwise noted.</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>Interrogatories on Defendant's part.</head>
				<p>//IMG_0490 and IMG_0492//<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Interrogatories to be administred to witneses to be produced on the parte behalf of S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick Barronet Def<expan>endan</expan>t at <expan>th</expan>e Suite of Forrest Ashfeild als Forrest Edmond Ashfeild Esq<expan>ui</expan>re Comp<expan>lainan</expan>t. </p>
 <p>
 1.) Imprimis doe you know the partyes Comp<expan>lainan</expan>t and Def<expan>endan</expan>ts or any or either and which of them how long have you known them or either of them Did you know Elinor Glanville dec<expan>eas</expan>ed the pl<expan>aintif</expan>fs Mother and William Goodrick Esq<expan>ui</expan>re deceased and Elianor<lb/>
 his wife als<unclear>e</unclear> deceased or either of them in their life time how long did you know them or either of them before their death and how long time since did they or either of them dye as you know beleive or have heard Declare.<lb/>
 2.) Item doe you live within the parish and Mannor of Tickenham in the County of Somersett and and how long have you lived there or are or have you been a Tennant unto or at any time held any lands within that Mannor who was the Landlord<lb/>
 or Landlady there or to whome Did you pay your Rent when you first lived or held Lands there how long did you live or continue there a Tennant or Inhabitant whether did you <add>know</add> William Goodrick Esq<expan>ui</expan>re deceased the pl<expan>aintiff</expan>s Grandfather whether was he<lb/>
 <unclear>reented</unclear> Own<expan>e</expan>r of the said Mannor or did he usually receive the rents of the Tennants there who rec<expan>eiv</expan>ed <expan>th</expan>e rents or proffitts ariseing there after his death and to whome and for whose use did the Tennants there pay their rents as you know beleive<lb/>
 or have heard Was the pl<expan>aintiffs</expan> Mother after the said William Goodrickes death taken and acknowledged as the Owner of the said Mannor and did she continue till the time of her death were the rents there usually received by her or such persons<lb/>
 as she appointed as you know or beleive Declare what you know or beleive herein with your reasons.<lb/>
 3.) Item whether did you see any or either and which and how many of the Deeds Evidences and writings now produced and showne to you sealed and Executed by any or either and which and how many of the partyes thereto or persons therein named and<lb/>
 did you subscribe or indorse your name as a witness thereto and is your name there written of your handwriting as you know or beleive who Else was a witness thereto are or is he she or they dead or liveing and how long since did he shee or<lb/>
 they dye as you know or beleive are you acquainted with his her or their handwriting as you know or beleive Declare.<lb/>
 4.) Item whether were you acquainted with any or either of the persons whoe names are subscribed or indorsed as witnenes to the sealing and delivery of any or either and which of the writings now produced and shewne to you Are any or either<lb/>
 and which and how many <add>of them</add> dead or liveing how long since did they or either of them dye as you know beleive or have heard Are you acquainted with the hand writing of them and which of them are or is their or either of their names soe<lb/>
 subsribed or indorsed of his her or their own proper handwriting as you know or beleive declare.<lb/>
 5.) Item whether were you a witnes to any or either and which of the receipts now produced and shewn to you Did you see such receipts or either of them signed by the persons therein named and did you subscribe your name as a witness thereto and is your name here written<lb/>
 of your handwriting who els was or were witnesses there to besides your self are you acquainted with their or either of their hand writing are or is <expan>th</expan>e name or names of either of the witnesses there to of his <add>her</add> or their handwriting as you know or beleive Declare.<lb/>
 6.) Item whether did you see the said Elinor Glanville seale and and as her act and deed deliver the Deed poll now produced and shewn to you bearing date thirtyeth day of July in the yeare of our Lord one thousand seven hundred and five and dyd you indorse<lb/>
 The appointm<expan>en</expan>t your name as a Witness thereto and is your name there written of your own hand writing who else was present and a witness thereto besides yourself are their names thereon indorsed of their own handwriting as you know or beleive Was the said Elinor<lb/>
 Glanville at that time of good sound memory and understanding as you know or beleive Declare.<lb/>
 7.) Item whether did you see the Indenture now produced and shewne to you bearing date the thirteenth day of March one thousand six hundred ninity Eight sealed and delivered by the said Elinor Glanville and Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re <add>or either of them</add> and did you indorse your<lb/>
 name as a witness there to Declare.<lb/>
 8.) Item whether doe you know beleive or have heard that the Comp<expan>lainan</expan>t had at any time a Lease from his Mother of a Tenement in the West <unclear>owne</unclear> of Tickenham or have you heard that his Mother at any time put him into the possession of her Tenement there<lb/>
 what is <expan>th</expan>e yearly vallue of that Tenement as you know as you know or beleive Did she leave give or deliver him any stock thereupon how long did he live there and how and in what manner Did he mannge that Tenement how soone did he leave the same Doe<lb/>
 you know or have you heard that he offerred to sell or dispose of his Lease thereof to any person and persons and to whome and for what Declare what you know beleive or have heard to this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y.<lb/>
 9.) Item whether did you see the Deed poll now produced and shewn to you dated the Eighteenth day of December in the yeare of our Lord one thousand six hundred ninty nine sealed and delivered by the pl<expan>aintiffs</expan> his Act and Deed and did you indorse your<lb/>
 name as witness thereto and is your name there written of your own hand writing whether were you acquainted with Walter Attwood gent<expan>leman</expan> deceased whose name is subscribed as witness to the said Deed poll now produced and shewne to you<lb/>
 and with his hand writing how long since Did he dye whether is the name Walter Attwood thereto subscribed as a witness and likewise the name Walter Attwood subscribed as a witness to the Receipt thereon indorsed of this the said Walter<lb/>
 Attwoods own hand writing as you know or beleive Whether Did you see the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t signe the said receipt indorsed on the Deed poll now produced and did you subscribe your name as a witness thereto Declare.<lb/>
 10.) Item whether were you well acquainted with the said Elinor Glanville in her life time and often conversant with her have you at any time or times had any discourse with her relating to the pl<expan>aintiff </expan>as to his behaviour and way of liveing<lb/>
 have you heard her complaine of undutifullness towards her and of his Extravagancy and keeping bad company and spending and wasting money and that he would not by any meanes be reclaimed have you at any time heard her declare or<lb/>
 Express how or in what manner she had or intended to dispose of her Estate If yea! sett forth the purport or substance of such discourse as neare as you can and how long such discourse happened before her death Did she express or <add>declare</add><lb/>
 any and what reason for such resoluc<expan>i</expan>on (if yea) <add>declare &amp;</add> sett forth the same as neare you can.<lb/>
 11.) Item whether at anytime before and how long before the death of the said Elinor Glanville Did she break upp housekeeping Did you heare or understand from her the reason or cause for her so doing or what induced her to doe as you know or beleive<lb/>
 whether did she retire to Bristoll London or Elswhere Doe you know or have you heard whose hous or to what place she removed her goods from Tickenham Did Shee Express or declare what induced her soe to doe Declare what you know beleive or have<lb/>
 heard to this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y with your reasons and circumstances at large.<lb/>
 12.) Item whether did the pl<expan>aintiff</expan> in his Mothers lifetime lay claime to all or any of her Estate or interr<unclear>uset</unclear> her or her tennants in the management thereof or threaten to enter thereon and take away their Corne when sowne Declare what you know or<lb/>
 have heard the pl<expan>aintiff</expan> declare and say touching her Estate and what his intenc<expan>i</expan>ons were thereabout.<lb/>
 13.) Item whether were you a Tennant to Mrs Elinor Glanville in her lifetime and for any and how many years before her death Doe you know of any meeting between the pl<expan>aintiff</expan> and his Mother at the house of Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re in or about<lb/>
 August or September one thousand seven hundred and four were you desired to be there and bring some money with you and did you accordingly meet them there and carry any and how much money with you upon what occassion was such<lb/>
 meeting had as you know or beleive or what was done or to be done with the moneys you carried thither Did you then heare what discourse then passed between the said Mr Gorges and <expan>th</expan>e pl<expan>aintiff</expan> and his mother if yea sett forth <unclear>of</unclear> Effect and substance of<lb/>
 such discource and what was done there upon as neare as you can.<lb/>
 14.) Item whether after such meeting did you by order of the p<expan>lain</expan>t<expan>iffs</expan> Mother for any and how long time or for any and how many years afterwards pay the p<expan>lain</expan>t<expan>iff </expan>any and how much money weekly or quarterly for his maintenance Did he at any time and for how long<lb/>

//IMG_043 and IMG_0494//<lb/>
 after that <unclear>dyett</unclear> and lodge at your house or at some other and what place and how did the p<expan>lain</expan>t<expan>iff</expan> behave himself after such allowance made him Declare.<lb/>
 15.) Item were you at any time before the said Elinor Glanvills death and how long before her death ordered to pay the p<expan>lain</expan>t<expan>iff</expan> noe more money and for what reason were <unclear>you so forbad</unclear> as you know or beleive Did she Express or declare any reason<lb/>
 therefore (If yea) sett forth what reason she gave and the substance of what she said or declared to you on that occasion Did you acquaint the p<expan>lain</expan>t<expan>iff</expan> with such her orders what <unclear>any</unclear> were Did he <unclear>then</unclear> thereto sett forth the same as neare as you can.<lb/>
 16.) Item whether did the p<expan>lain</expan>t<expan>iff</expan> upon any occasion declare that he was or did intend to turne protestant Did he give his reason for so doing or declare any re<unclear>soluc<expan>i</expan>on</unclear> of procureing his mothers Estate thereby sett forth what discourse passed between you and him or <unclear>xxx</unclear><lb/>
 occasion as neare as you can.<lb/>
 17.) Item whether did you at any time and how long since live with the said Elinor Glanville as her servant whether did she dureing the time you were with her go to Bristoll or any other and what place in order to reside or stay for some time what<lb/>
 direcc<expan>i</expan>on or orders had you from her <unclear>In hole</unclear> her son the plaintiffe came to her house at Tickenham in her absence Declare.<lb/>
 18.) Item whether were you at any time and how long since a servant to Mrs Elinor Glanville whether dureing your stay with her have you heard the <unclear>complainte</unclear> of the p<expan>lain</expan>t<expan>iffs </expan>Extravagance and were you ordered by her to <unclear>illegible...</unclear><lb/>
 or any other things that had been pawned by him and did you pay the debt and redeeme the same accordingly sett forth where the same were pawned and the persons names to whome the same were pawned and what was by you<lb/>
 paid for Redempc<expan>i</expan>on thereof as neare as you can.<lb/>
 19.) Item doe you remember about what time the p<expan>laintif</expan>f returned from France were you then Rennant to Mrs Glanville Did she then order you to pay him any money to buy him Cloaths or other necessarys or to pay him any weekly<lb/>
 sum for his maintenance sett forth the <unclear>time</unclear> as neare as you <add>cann</add> and what sum<expan>m</expan>e or sum<expan>m</expan>es of money she ordered you to pay him presently and how much weekly afterwards and how long you continued such payments whether <unclear>yea</unclear><lb/>
 any part of such allowance to be deducted for his dyett or board while he lived with you what was the reason she <unclear>appointed</unclear> such payments weekly as you know or beleive Declare.<lb/>
 20.) Item whether you were a servant to or intimately acquiainted with the p<expan>laintif</expan>f and his mother dureing the p<expan>laintif</expan>f minority whether did she educate him at schoole or <unclear>anie</unclear> such maintenance as her Estate would aford till he came of age Did he at any time<lb/>
 propose to settle him to any profession or settle him on bussiness what was the reason he was not settled or imployed as you know or beleive what have you heard Mrs Glanville say or declare at this occassion Did the p<expan>laintif</expan>f shew any inclinac<expan>i</expan>on<lb/>
 thereto or decline the same and how did the said Mrs Glanville <unclear>relent</unclear> the same have you heard and how often have you heard her complaine of the p<expan>laintif</expan>f unwillingness to take any imployment or bussinese on him but on the contrary of his<lb/>
 spending &amp; keeping idle company &amp; bringing idle persons to her house at unseasonable times &amp; that she was afraid of being in her house Declare what you know beleive or have heard to this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y w<expan>i</expan>th yo<expan>u</expan>r reasons &amp; circumstances for such your knowledge or beleife<lb/>
 21.) Item whether after the determinac<expan>i</expan>on of <expan>th</expan>e suits between the said Mrs Glanville and her husband Glanville have you heard her declare any feare she had of <expan>th</expan>e p<expan>laintif</expan>fs holding correspondance with Mr Glanville or that she feared the p<expan>laintif</expan>f would be a meanes to<lb/>
 of betraying her into his power or anything to that or the like effect Declare.<lb/>
 22.) Item whether were you acquainted with Mrs Elinor Glanville for any <add><expan>th</expan>e p<expan>laintif</expan>fs mother</add> for any and how many years before her death and have you had any recconings or accounts with her received Letters from her or transacted any bussiness with her (If yea) sett forth the<lb/>
 nature of the concerns you had with her and the business relating to such accounts whether for rents letting her Estate or otherwise whether dureing such your acquiaintance or transacc<expan>i</expan>ons did you observe her a woman of good sence and<lb/>
 understanding or was she delirious Frenzy or void of understanding whether in making her bargaines letting her Estate stocking her lands and passing her accounts did she act sensible and as one that understood the bussiness she was about<lb/>
 Sett forth what you know or beleive touching this Interrogatory with your reasons and circumstances for such your knowledge or beleif.<lb/>
 23.) Item whether have you at any time and how long before the said Elinor Glanvilles death done bussiness for her or been imployed by her (if yea) sett forth such bussiness perticulers and the direcc<expan>i</expan>ons <unclear>rec<expan>eiv</expan>ed</unclear> from her thereabout Did she take care for<lb/>
 your payment how came you to be imployed by her how long did you serve her were her direcc<expan>i</expan>ons and orders sensibly given and did you pursue such orders and why did you not have you at any time <unclear>signed</unclear> the reasonableness or unreasonableness<lb/>
 of such orders were her arguments thereabouts rationale or not sett forth the perticulers of such arguments as near as you can.<lb/>
 24.) Item whether in the said Elinor Glanvills lifetime and for any and how many years before her death were you a Bayliff or agent to assist her in mannageing or stocking her Estate or a servant in her house or did work for her sett forth the nature of such work.<lb/>
 you so did or bussiness you were imployed about whether did you from time to time receive orders direcc<expan>i</expan>ons or instrucc<expan>i</expan>ons from herself or from time to time render to her an account what you had done were her direcc<expan>i</expan>ons and orders sensibly given or<lb/>
 proper for the bussness you were imployed about whether or no was she carefull in seeing her bussiness done and taking your account to and paying your wages Sett forth the truth of what you know beleive or have heard to this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y with your<lb/>
 reasons and circumstances at large.<lb/>
 25.) Item whether were you an apprentice to the said Mrs Glanville at the time of her death how long had you lived with her before she dyed whether dureing the time you lived with her did she order and direct what was to be done and not to<lb/>
 be done in her family was she dureing the time you lived with her sensible what she did or capable of ordering her servants or was she uncapable by reason of meloncholly frenzy or madness and also sett forth in what perticulers she seemed to you to <add>be</add><lb/>
 frenzy or mad.<lb/>
 26.) Item whether was you or your late husband imployed by the said Elinor Glanville to look after her house goods and stock and mann<expan>a</expan>ge her Estate either in her absence or whilest she resided in Tickenham whether did you or your late husband<lb/>
 often in her absence receive Letters or written orders or direcc<expan>i</expan>ons from her about managment of her affaires are the Letters and papers now produced and shewen to you such Letters or instrucc<expan>i</expan>ons <add>as</add> you so received where did you find the<unclear>m</unclear><lb/>
 Letters and papers have they been in your house or in your husbands Custody ever since you rec<expan>eiv</expan>ed them till this time Declare.<lb/>
 27.) Item whether did the said Mrs Glanville usually lodge at your house when she came to or made any stay in Bristoll Did the p<expan>laintif</expan>f also lodge in your house when she did or come thither often to vissitt her and Eat and drink with her Did the said<lb/>
 Mrs Glanville usually seeme pleased with his company or give you any direcc<expan>i</expan>ons for his entertainiment or pay you for entertaining of him or give you any direcc<expan>i</expan>ons to supply him with money or any other necessarys Declare the Truth.<lb/>
 28.) Item whether was the said Mrs Glanville at the time of her death indebted to you or owed you any money (If yea) sett forth the sum<expan>m</expan>e or sum<expan>m</expan>es of money she owed you and upon what account and how and for what she became so indebted whether hath the Def<expan>endan</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r<lb/>
 Henry Goodrick or any other by his order or with his consent since her death paid you any money as and for a Debt owing by her or as and for a Debt <unclear>owing</unclear> by the p<expan>laintif</expan>f whether was such Debt contracted by her or was it money the p<expan>laintif</expan>f had of you how came you<lb/>
 to lett him have that money was it received <add>of you</add> or taken upp from you with his mothers privity Did she agree to pay it you or did she always refuse to pay the same and for what reason as you know or beleive Declare the Truth.<lb/>
 29.) Item whether hath the Def<expan>endan</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick since the said Mrs Glanvills death paid any of the debts she owed at her death or any or either and which and how many of the Legacys given in and by her will (if yea) sett forth the perticuler <unclear>Debt</unclear><lb/>
 Debts legacys or legacys so paid and when and to whome and how you know the same.<lb/>
 30.) Item whether after the death of the said Mrs Glanville Did the Def<expan>endan</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick give <unclear>mourning</unclear> to her two daughters being the p<expan>laintif</expan>fs Sisters or either of them and to what value and whether did he also give them or one of them her gold watch and<lb/>
 all or the greatest part of her wearing apparrell and household stuffe Doe you know of any other household stuffe the said Mrs Elinor Glanville left at her death besides what the pl<expan>aintif</expan>fs sisters had delivered them (if yea) sett forth <expan>th</expan>e perticulers and what<lb/>
 become thereof and in whose Custody the same was at her death.<lb/>
 31.) Item whether hath the Defend<expan>an</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick ever since <expan>th</expan>e s<expan>ai</expan>d Mrs Glanvills death given them or either of them an yearly allowance for their maintenance and support and hath such allowance been paid them or either of them quarterly Sett forth<lb/>
 how much such allowance hath amounted to yearly or q<expan>ua</expan>rterly &amp; how long the same hath <unclear>been paid</unclear> or allowed to each of them whether was such allowance more or less than Mrs Glanvilles allowed them in her lifetime Declare the truth.<lb/>

//verso, IMG_0495 and IMG_0496//<lb/>
 32.) Item whether were all or most &amp; the houses outhouses in Tickenham and att Backwell being the said Mrs Glanviles Estates Togeather with the walls and fences thereto belonging very much out of repaire and some fallen down and others<lb/>
 ready to fall downe whether hath the Def<expan>endan</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick since her death repaired severall of the houses outhouses walls and fences in order to make them Tennantable How much in your Judgment may the said Def<expan>endan</expan>t have<lb/>
 Expended thereabout hath any thing been laid out thereabout save what was absolutely <add>necessary</add> Whether are all <add>the</add> houses and outhouses repaired or what will it in your Judgment yett Cost to putt the same in tennantable repair<lb/>
 as you know or beleive Declare what you know or beleive herein with your reasons.<lb/>
 33.) Item whether were you or have you been a workman imployed in repairing the said houses walls and fences or as an Overseer in looking after the work and paying the workmen whether hath there been any more tymber<lb/>
 cutt from of the premisses then hath been absolutely necessary for repairing the same Do you know of any Tymber that hath been sold of the Estate since Mrs. Glanvills death or imployed about any other use than for the<lb/>
 repairing of the same Declare.<lb/>
 34.) Item whether were you well acquainted with the hand writing of the said Elinor Glanville or corresponded with her by Letters are the severall Letters papers and other writnigs now produced and shewn to you the proper hand<lb/>
 writing of the said Elinor Glanville as you know or beleive Declare.<lb/>
 35.) Item doe you know the Estate late of of the said Elinor Glanville in Tickenham aforesaid what is the reall yearly vallue of all the Farms and Tenements there to be lett <add>at</add> a <unclear>Rack</unclear> rent how much thereof or what Tenements are there now<lb/>
 out in leases for lives or for long terms of years determinable on one two or three lives sett forth the yearly vallue of such Tenements or farmes as are lett at <unclear>Rack</unclear> rents and the yearly vallues of such Tenements as are not for<lb/>
 lives under small rents as near as you can.<lb/>
 36.) Item doe you know the Farme called Backwell Park what is the yearly vallue thereof or at what rent hath the same been usually lett Declare.<lb/>
 37.) Item what is the present yearly rent payable out of the Mannor of Rodney Stoke by Tennants there was any part thereof in hand or rented at a Rack rent when the said Mrs Glanville dyed Declare what you know or<lb/>
 beleive herein with your reasons.<lb/>
 38.) Item where and in whose Custody were the severall Letters papers and other writings now produced and shewn to you found at the Death of the said Elinor Glanville Set forth the time place &amp; manner of your finding the same.<lb/>
 </p>
 <p>
 Will Banastre<lb/>
 Tho<expan>mas</expan> Oldfeild<lb/>
 <unclear>xxxx Thruppe</unclear><lb/>
 Sam<expan>uel</expan> Fox<lb/>

</p></div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>