<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://cwrc.ca/templates/css/tei.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Sample Document Title</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p/>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc sameAs="http://www.cwrc.ca">
				<p>Created from original research by members of CWRC/CSÉC unless
					otherwise noted.</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"/></xenoData></teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>Depositions on the Part of the Complainant (2)</head>
				<p>(3)
</p>
 <p>
 24.) To the Twentieth and Four and Twentyeth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That he believes the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother valued and loved her Butterflyes better than She did her Children and was kinder to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and her Apprentice Girles than she was to them And Sayes that he hath heard her say she was afraid her Children would murder<lb/>
her (but of what reason She had for so saying knows not.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 James Walker of <unclear>Kenn</unclear> in the County of Somersett Carpenter Aged Nine and Forty Yeares or thereabouts Sworne and Exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) &amp; 10.) To the Seventh and Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that he hath known and been acquainted w<expan>i</expan>th the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother for Twenty Yeares and upwards and lived within Three Miles of her for that time or longer And Sayes that he hath heard some of her Neighbours say she was not a Woman in her Sences And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t was &amp; is<lb/>
of the same opinion and gives the following instance as his reason therefore That about five Yeares agoe he was sent for by the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother to repaire her Water Grist Mill at Tickenham and when he came after some little discourse she told him she would have the Great Wheel of the Mill put on her house that she might see<lb/>
how it did goe w<expan>hi</expan>ch he told her could not be done &amp; thereupon left her And saith that about a yeare after he went to speak with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother about taking the said Mill and mett with her about Ten a Clock in the Morning at a house of hers in Tickenham afores<expan>ai</expan>d called the Folly Scituate upon a Hill where she then<lb/>
dwelt and upon his coming there he found the doors of the house open and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother by herself with a Whipp in her hand barelegged and bareheaded and without any Cloths on her back saue one pettycoate walking very fast round and about three or Four Chairs She had placed in the Middle of the Roome and<lb/>
Whipping the said Chairs crying Ride Bess Ride, Ride Bess, Ride and so continued to do for sometime at length this Depon<expan>en</expan>t spoke to her and told her he was come to take her Mills of her if she would lett them, she answered this Depon<expan>en</expan>t she would not lett the said Mill but would have them putt up here meaning on the Hill<lb/>
where her house called the Folly stood and that she would make a <unclear>Mow Barton</unclear> where the said Mills then stood to putt her hay in, This Depon<expan>en</expan>t then told her this Hill was not a fitt place to sett the Mill on because there was no Water on w<expan>hi</expan>ch the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother said she could turn the River and bring Water to the Mill<lb/>
and then she would Walk a pace about and round the Chairs Whipping them as before and saying Ride Bess, Ride, Ride Bess, Ride and between every sentence or two she would speake to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t would walk fast round the Chair and cry ride, Bess, ride, this Depon<expan>en</expan>t then asked her whether she was rideing and<lb/>
what Bess she meant, she answered this Depon<expan>en</expan>t she was Rideing to Bristoll for they were goeing to make her make <del>her</del> will to give away that that she could not sell, and lookt very earnest on this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and asked him how she could do that and than fell a Whipping the Chairs and saying as before And as to Bess she said Bess<lb/>
had buried somewhat that I doubt must be dugg up again before either she or I can be at quiet, but named, No Bess. nor told what was to be dugg up, And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t left her Whipping the Chairs as aforesaid And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further saith that he was about 18 or 20 Yeares Since a Servant to or working for one Doctor<lb/>
Baylys at <unclear>Hornesham</unclear> in the County of Wilts<expan>hire</expan> who cured Mad people and he believes the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was Mad for that the said An<unclear>ōns</unclear> and Frolicks were like those of severall persons he had seen while he lived with or work’t for the said Doctor &amp; were there to be cured for madness.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Elizabeth Knight Widow a Witness already Sworne &amp; Exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part and now againe produced sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
11.) &amp; 12.) To the Eleaventh and Twelfth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes she saith That she never heard the Def<expan>endan</expan>t Mr. Thomas Edwards say or declare that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was Mad or anything to that purpose Neither did this Depon<expan>en</expan>t ever heare the said Mr. Edwards say or declare any thing touching the reason and End of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts<lb/>
Mothers making the Will and settlement in que<expan>sti</expan>on or either of them.<lb/>
13.) To the Thirteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y she saith that she hath <add>heard</add> the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother oftentimes in her lifetime in discourseing with <add>her</add> touching her settleing of her Estates say That she had made a Deed or Deeds before her Marriage with Mr. Glanvile and left the same in the hands of Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re late of Wraxall<lb/>
in the Country of Somersett deceased which said Mr. Gorges was for many Yeares one of the Justices of the peace for the County of Somersett and a Gentleman of a good Estate and alwayes Esteemed in the County where he lived a Man of great Wisdome understanding integrity and reputac<expan>i</expan>on And further<lb/>
saith that when this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and the said Mrs. Glanvile had any such discourse together she said she had reserved the power to herself in such Deed or Deeds And that she had never gott a groat by either of her husbands and could give it to the Depon<expan>en</expan>t if she pleased for dost thee think Bess that I<lb/>
would give it to them when I gott nothing by their Fathers.<lb/>
15.)To the Fifteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y she saith that she never had or rec<expan>eiv</expan>ed any Deed or Deeds whatsoever from the said Edward Gorges in the precedent Deposic<expan>i</expan>on named to her knowledge or beleife but she hath carried &amp; rec<expan>eiv</expan>ed severall He<unclear>reditaments?</unclear> and from the said Edward Gorges and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother.<lb/>
22.) To the Two and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y she saith That she knows not or can give any instance of disobedience of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t his Brother or sister or any or either of them to their Mother or any Act or Acts of extravagancy that they or either of them was or were guilty of, And saith that dureing all the time<lb/>
that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived with Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and all the rest of her Children behaved themselves dutifull and obedient to her.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Stephen Chapmann Gent<expan>leman</expan> a Witness sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part and now on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
6.) To the sixth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Deponent saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was owner of the Manner of Tickenham and the <unclear>Dameanes</unclear> thereof were reputed to be worth ab<expan>ou</expan>t One hundred and Twenty pounds <unclear>Around</unclear> besides the Ren<unclear>ncion</unclear> of 8 or 10 small Tenem<expan>en</expan>ts of about £12 or £14 <unclear>Annuity?</unclear> to the best of this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts remembrance<lb/>
And saith that she had an Estate at Barkwell called Barkwell Parkes w<expan>hi</expan>ch this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath formerly lett for her at one hundred pounds per <unclear>Annuity</unclear> And she also had the Third parte of the Mannor of Rodney Stoke but this Depon<expan>en</expan>t can’t sett forth the Yearly Value thereof but says the way the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother<lb/>
took to raise money thereon was by takeing Fines for granting Estates by Leases or otherwise which is gen<expan>er</expan>ally the way of raising money there.<lb/>
8.)To the Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not manage her Estate as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath heard and beleives like a Woman of discretion but says that he hath heard and beleives she was a considerable <unclear>looser</unclear> by turning out good Tenants and keeping her Estate Sometimes in her own hands<lb/>
13.) To the Thirteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That he doth not know of any Deeds of settlement made by the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Father &amp; Mother of all or any part of her Estate on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts or his Father but hath heard from the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t that there were some Deeds made whereby the Estate<unclear>s</unclear> were settled on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his<lb/>
Father and were left in the hands of one Mr. Gorges who was a Man of a good Estate and good Character Except one Deed to lead the Uses of a Fine proved by this Depon<expan>en</expan>t on his Exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ac<expan>i</expan>on on the Depon<expan>en</expan>ts part.<lb/>
16.) &amp; 26) To the sixteenth and six and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>ys this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath heard and beleives all or great part of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers Estate was the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Grandmothers before 'twas hers and before the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Grandmother 'twas the Estate of one Rice Davis Esq<expan>ui</expan>re who was the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers<lb/>
Grandfather, and that he purchased all or the greatest part of the said Mann<expan>er</expan> of Tickenham as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath heard and beleives And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Father was a Lymner &amp; rented an house in London of Fourscore pounds <unclear>∞ Annuity</unclear> as he hath heard and a man of good credit and repute and lived<lb/>
comfortabley &amp; quietly w<expan>i</expan>th his Wife all his lifetime for anything this Depon<expan>en</expan>t ever heard to the contrary.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 John Lyne of the parish of Tickenham aforesaid Husbandman aged Fifty yeares or thereabouts sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
/4.) To the Fourth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith he was born and breed in Tickenham aforesaid and hath there <unclear>&amp;</unclear> in the <unclear>next</unclear> parish lived all the dayes of his life And he hath known and been acquainted w<expan>i</expan>th the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother ever since she married his Father and rented Estates of her Severall times And also sayes that she hath<lb/>
often heard her complain of the disrespect of her Children and seem discontented at it And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith he never saw or knew of any disrespect they or either of them were Guilty of towards her but that they generally behaved themselves with duty and obedience to her but that she carried herself very hard to them<lb/>
many times and would not allow them such things as in this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Judgement were proper for them or as persons of her Estate and Rank <unclear>---ase dar</unclear> and the this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts once paid the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts by his Mothers Orders twenty Five Shillings w<expan>hi</expan>ch she promised to allow in his Rent, but when the Depon<expan>en</expan>t paid her<lb/>
Rent she refused to allow the same and the same is still unpaid and due to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t at the time he so paid him the s<expan>ai</expan>d Five and Twenty Shillings that if he did not lett him have Some money <add>he</add> must complain to the overseers of the parish for Releife or to that effect.<lb/>
5.) To the Fifth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That he knows not of any allowance the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t had from his Mother for his Maintenance but hath heard she once allowed him Four Shillings Week but how long the same was so paid or allowed to him knoweth not Neither doth this Depon<expan>en</expan>t know or ever heard of any Debts the<lb/>
Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t ever contracted or that he was extravagant or disorderly in his life <unclear>Comdtacion</unclear> or otherwise.<lb/>
8.) To the Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not manage her Estate like a woman of discretion or Managem<expan>en</expan>t <unclear>.er</unclear> unless <unclear>he or she?</unclear> could lett the same at a greater Yearly Rent or for more then the same was worth She would keep keep it in her hands and make but little of it. And that she would not<lb/>
plow her lands in the Com<expan>m</expan>on Feild when they were in her hand as others did but would Plow them and cutt all manner of Weeds and Thistles and make them into hay as she would afterwards call it.<lb/>
9 &amp; 10.) To the Ninth and Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith he knows <unclear>n</unclear>ot in what manner the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lived in her house as to housekeeping but sayes she lived but a little while in a place and would often move from one of her own houses to another and from <add>one</add> Village to another, sometimes she would live at<lb/>
Bristoll and sometimes at London but her reasons for so doeing knows not And further says that for 3 or 4 Yeares before her death she gen<expan>er</expan>ally kept but two parish Apprentice Girls as her servants and attendants And sayes that he hath heard she had Magotty Tricks.<lb/>

</p>
 <p>
 <unclear>IMG_0502 and IMG_0503</unclear><lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Thomas Jacob a Witness already Sworne &amp; examined on the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part and now again produced sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth<lb/>
To the Fourth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts <unclear>...</unclear> Brothers and Sisters dureing so much of the time this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived at Tickenham Backwell <unclear>as Tent.</unclear> to their Mother did alwayes behave themselves very dutifull and Obedient to their said Mother for ought this Depon<expan>en</expan>t ever saw to the contrary But<lb/>
that she Generally carryed herself very rigid and Severe towards them And saith that for some of the time this Depon<expan>en</expan>t <unclear>s</unclear>o Rented her Estate she maintained her Children mean and indifferent and sometimes boarded them out where she could have them maintained cheapest And kept very mean in their <unclear>.....bad picture</unclear><lb/>
5.) To the Fifth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t had after the rate of Thirty pounds <unclear>Annu<expan>ity</expan></unclear> allowed him by his Mother for his Maintenance Which this Depon<expan>en</expan>t paid the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t for one half Yeare and no longer and then the same was discontinued by Order of his said Mother And <unclear>-----</unclear> times <unclear>---</unclear><lb/>
the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was allowed by order of the Lord Keeper Eight Shillings <expan>per</expan> Week for his Boarding and maintenance w<expan>i</expan>th this Depon<expan>en</expan>t paid to the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t for about two Yeares by his Mothers direcc<expan>i</expan>on And that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t allwayes seemed well satisfied w<expan>i</expan>th such his said allowance And beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t did not Lend or contract<lb/>
Debts And saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was not extravagant or disorderly as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t ever saw or beleived.<lb/>
6.) To the sixth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That he beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers Estate at Tickenham and Barkwell in poss<expan>ess</expan>ion and <unclear>Renercion</unclear> to be worth Three hundred pounds a Yeare or upwards but what the Estate of Rodney Stoake is Annually worth knows not.<lb/>
8.) To the Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did lett her Estatesat the highest Rates she could gett and that severall of her Tennants left her Estates by reason she lett them at such great Rents And saith that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t so left her Estates for the Reasons aforesaid And Saith that when her<lb/>
Estate was in hand she managed the same very ordinary and not like a Woman of discretion often times letting the houses and buildings Run out of repaire and the Bounds and Fences thereof very much to Ruine.<lb/>
9.) To the Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y This Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lived in her house very meanly and not like a Woman of her Estate and Rank and managed the same very indifferently And very often moved from one of her houses To another from place to place And sometimes to Bristoll <unclear>----</unclear><lb/>
to London and seldome contained in any place to long, And saith that dureing all the time this Depon<expan>en</expan>t knew the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother she kept two parish Apprentice Girls, which was all the servants she had save that sometimes she had a Man and a Maid servant But kept but one of them<lb/>
at a time.<lb/>
7.) To the seventeenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did much delight in Butterflies, Flies, Worms and other Insects.<lb/>
19.) To the Nineteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that about Five or Six Y<expan>ea</expan>rs agoe to this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts best rememberance the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother sent for this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to Tickenham and amongst other discourse told him that she had made her Will and that she had given away her Estate and that now <unclear>Mr------</unclear><lb/>
the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t should never be the better for it whereupon this Depon<expan>en</expan>t asked her if she had given it to her son Richard to w<expan>hi</expan>ch she replyed no she had given it to her protestant Heir And thereupon this Depon<expan>en</expan>t told her he thought she had not done well to give it way from her Children who answered that<lb/>
they were one of her Children for she had putt her Children to Nurse and that the Nurse had changed them or to that effect.<lb/>
20.) To the Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was more affected or pleased with her Butterflies than any of her Children.<lb/>
24.) To the Four and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that whilst this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived at Barkwell in the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers Estate that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t had a design to Murder or poysen her and thereupon he asked her why she should fancy so for Murder would one time or other certainly <unclear>--</unclear><lb/>
discovered to which she replyed she did beleive he would do it but that he would one time or other ~~................~~ worry her out of her life.<lb/>
31.) For the One and Thirtieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that he never knew that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t or his Sisters did goe to see converse with or did hold any correspondence with Mr Glanvile the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers husband from the time he seperated from her to the time of her death but that he<lb/>
heard the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother say that she beleived the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t did correspond with him.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Joanna Bennett a Witness sworne and Exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part and now on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
4.) To the Fourth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t his Brother and Sisters behaved their selves towards their said Mother with only obedience for the time this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived with her or that ever she saw but that their said Mother would often times be severe to and angry with her said children<lb/>
on very triviall occasions in this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Judgement And sayes that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t his Mother had bred him no Scholar neither had she bred him to work, so that he was at a loss how to gett his own liveing And has also heard the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother say that she putt the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t to school for Sev<expan>er</expan>all<lb/>
Yeares but that he would not take to his learning.<lb/>
5th.) To the Fifth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That she hath heard that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did sometimes allow the Comp<expan>lainan</expan>t Some thing by the Week for his Maintenance but how much cannot sett forth and Sometimes she hath also heard the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not allow him anything And Saith she would <unclear>Take</unclear><lb/>
him at one Neighbours house, then take him home, and Shortly <unclear>table</unclear> him out again at another house and she hath heard some of the Neighbours say that they were not paid for such his tableing to this day and also saith she knows not or ever heard of any debts the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t Contracted, or that he was <unclear>ever</unclear><lb/>
extravagent or disorderly in his life conversac<expan>i</expan>on or otherwise.<lb/>
8.) &amp; 9.) To the Eighth and Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that she hath heard and beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not Manage her Estate like a Woman of discretion but that she would loose considerably by keeping it in her hand and <unclear>otherwise lind</unclear> alsoe Saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother <unclear>did not live xxxx</unclear><lb/>
house as to housekeeping like a Woman of her Estate but kept a Mean house and lived Sometimes without any drink in it That she was a very unsettled woman and would move her habitac<expan>i</expan>on many times in a Year without any reason as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t knew and she would rise often in the night and<lb/>
make up her Cloths to goe to Bristoll in the Morning but would not go in Severall Months And further saith That she kept onely two parish Apprentice Girls as her servants dureing the time this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived in her house with her.<lb/>
20.) &amp; 22.) To the Twentieth and Two and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t sayes That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother took more delight in her Doggs and walking abroad and Catching butterflies than she did in any thing else and sayes She cannot give any instance of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t or his brothers or Sisters disobedience to their <unclear>Mother</unclear><lb/>
or extravagance in their lives or otherwise.<lb/>
24.) To the Four and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y she saith That she <add>hath</add> heard the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother (after he was at law w<expan>i</expan>th her) say that she thought the pl<expan>aintif</expan>f would Murder her.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Richard Davis of Tickenham in the County of Somersett Charcoal maker Aged Sixty Six Yeares and upwards Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
4.) To the Fourth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y he saith That he hath lived in Tickenham aforesaid for Forty Yeares past or thereabout near the house where the pl<expan>aintif</expan>fs Mother dwelt, and <unclear>recited</unclear> an Estate of her many Yeares before and after she married her first husband Mr Ashfeild And saith that by <unclear>means thereof</unclear><lb/>
he was very often in the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers house and well acquainted with her Family And saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his Sister Mrs Mary Ashfeild alwayes behaved themselves very dutifull and Obedient to their Mother for ought this Depon<expan>en</expan>t ever saw but she carried herself very severe towards them <unclear>and</unclear><lb/>
that she Educated her said Children in different well but kept them generally very meane in Apparell and hath heard that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother made her daughter Ashfeild Capps of cloath as course as a porters Apron.<lb/>
5.) To the Fifth Interr<expan>ogato</expan>ry he saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did make him a Weekly allowance of Eight Shillings p<expan>er</expan> Week for Some time but for how long know not And saith that before such allowance made the pl<expan>aintif</expan>f he was forced to goe from one Gent<expan>lemans</expan> house to another and to serverall of the Neighbours houses <unclear>for subsistence</unclear><lb/>
6.) To the Sixth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y he saith that he beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers Estate in Tickenham and Backwell in poss<expan>ess</expan>ion and reverc<expan>i</expan>ons is Three hundred pounds and upwards but knows not the Value of her EState at Rodney Stoke.<lb/>
7 &amp; 8.) To the Seventh and Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes he saith that he lived very neare to the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother and was tennant to her for many Years as he hath already declared And saith that whilst her husband Mr Glanvile lived with her she lived very well but after she was sep<expan>er</expan>ated from him she lived in a Meane Manner and did not<lb/>
Act like a Woman of discretion And she would oftentimes lett her Estate to Strangers and poore Fellowes at great Rents and for more then they were worth who were not able to pay her and often times Run a way in her Debt Rather then lett the same to her Neighbours who were able to pay her at good Rents and as <unclear>much as the</unclear><lb/>
said Estates were worth And saith that she would take her EState and keep the same in her hands for considerable time but managed the same much to her disadvantage and was a considerable <unclear>looser</unclear> thereby.<lb/>
9.) To the Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y he saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lived in her house very meanly and did not manage it discreetly for sometimes she would have bread and sometimes none, but seldom brewed any drink or had any but what she had from a Publick house by a Bottle at a time That she would sometimes reside at <unclear>the</unclear><lb/>
Court house at Tickenham but seldome continued long in a place sometimes she would remove herself and goods from one of her houses in Tickenham to another, from one Village to another, sometimes goe and live at Bristol and Sometimes in London and <unclear>so</unclear> remove from place to place five or Six tymes<lb/>
a Yeare But for what causes she so removed this Depon<expan>en</expan>t knows not That she generally kept onely two parish or Apprentice Girles as her Servants and carried herself very severely and cruel to her servants and would whip them once or twice a day as this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t hath heard.<lb/>
11.) To the Eleventh Interr<expan>ogato</expan>ry he Saith That about four Years agoe he was arrested by order of the Defend<expan>an</expan>t Mr Thomas Edwards at the Suite of Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re (since dec<expan>eas</expan>ed) who was one of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers Trustees To which <unclear>acc<expan>i</expan>on</unclear> this Depon<expan>en</expan>t gave an appearance And a few dayes after this Depon<expan>en</expan>t was arrested<lb/>
he went to the said Mr Gorges house in Wraxall in the County of Somersett and told him that he had been arrested at his suite and desired the said Mr Gorges to lett this Depon<expan>en</expan>t know for what Cause 'twas done who said he did not know the reason but ordered this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to go to Mr Edwards and enquire why he had<lb/>
made use of his name which this Depon<expan>en</expan>t did accordingly And saith that the said Mr Edwards then told him that he beleived the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was Mad for soe doeing and beleived that Bess Knight (<unclear>m</unclear>eaneing a Servant that then lived with her) would make her doe any thing And thereupon there were<lb/>
no farther pr<expan>o</expan>ceedings in the said Acc<expan>i</expan>on.<lb/>
13.) To the Thirteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That about Four Yeares past he hath heard &amp; been informed by Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother made a Deed of Settlement on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Father and his Heires forever of all her Estate at Tickenham and elsewhere and the same Deed<lb/>
was deposited and had been in the Custody of the said Mr Gorges in a Box with other writeings and Sayes he hath heard the said Mr Gorges also say the reason why the Compli<expan>anan</expan>ts mother made such Deed was because Mr Glanvile should not diminish her Estate and wast it from her Children And further saith that the<lb/>
said Mr Gorges also told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t that while the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts mother and Mr Glanvile were at Law together the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother or Mr Edwards or one of them sent to the said Mr Gorges for the said Box of writeings wherein the said Deed of Settlement was <add>and</add> that the said Mr Gorges had sent the said Box with the said<lb/>
Deed and all the writeings therein either to the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother or to the said Mr Edwards or one of them but knows not to w<expan>hi</expan>ch nor doth this Depon<expan>en</expan>t remember by whome he said the same was so sent And further says that Mr Gorges was a Man of an undoubted reputac<expan>i</expan>on und<expan>e</expan>rstanding &amp; Integrity<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Sarah Smith Wife of Thomas Smith a Witness Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part and now on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
22) To the Two and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith she cannot give any Instance neither hath she heard of any Acts of undutifullness and disobedience of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t or his brother or Sisters or either of them towards their said Mother other than that their said Mother told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t so neither <unclear>doth know or</unclear><lb/>
ever heard that they or any of them were ever extravagant or disorderly in their way of liveing convercac<expan>i</expan>on or otherwise.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 W<expan>llia</expan>m Wall of the Parish of <unclear>Kenn</unclear> in the County of Somersett Husbandman aged about Forty Yeares Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) &amp; 8th.) To the Seventh and Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That he lived within less than a quarter of a Mile for many Yeares of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Motherabout Seven Yeares Since he took an Estate of her for three Yeares, of the Value of Four and Twenty pounds p<expan>er</expan> Ann<expan>u</expan>m, and when this Depon<expan>en</expan>t had lived in it some <unclear>time</unclear><lb/>
above one Yeare, she sent to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t between Twelve and one a Clock at Night to come up pr<expan>e</expan>sently to her at the Courthouse at Tickenham and bring her and her goods down to this Dep<expan>onen</expan>ts house but this Depon<expan>en</expan>t haveing been at a Neighbouring Fair and drank a little refused to go that night to the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother but <unclear>so xxxxx</unclear><lb/>
word he would come the next morning, On which the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother the next morning sent to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and ordered him to turn out of her Estate or she would <unclear>hunt</unclear> him out of the Country and turned in her own Cattle and other of her Tenants on this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts and Eating and Spoiled all his Grass, and forced this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to <unclear>take</unclear><lb/>
out the day after and rent a little Estate hard by which obliged this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to turn his Cows all the Summer into the Moor much to his damage And for such and many such like <unclear>acc<expan>i</expan>ons</unclear> as those this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleives and he has heard the Neighbours say she was not. aWoman of discretion but on the Contrary crazy and out of her sences.<lb/>
And this Deponienit further saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not Manage her Estate to her Advantage but much to her <add>dis</add>advantage for that she would over Value her Estates so much she could gett no Tenants for them and then she kept them in her own hands and made very little of them, and also saith That she would <unclear>over</unclear><lb/>
Value her Hay and if she could not gett as much as she Generally asked for a Mow, She would keep it till twas rotten <unclear>juso ming</unclear> that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath heard her Agent sold a Mow of Hay for w<expan>hi</expan>ch she was once offered Seven pounds for Three pounds or there abouts.<lb/>
9.) To the Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lived in so mean a Manner as to house keeping, that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleives many of her Tenants lived better and Sayes he beleives she was not in her right Mind for that she was <add>very</add>unsettled and alwayes moveing from one <add>house or</add> place to another and particularly this Depon<expan>en</expan>t <unclear>heard?</unclear><lb/>
she called this Depon<expan>en</expan>t one day to go with her from her house at Tickenham called the Court house to her house there called the Folly intending to leave the Courthouse and live at the Folly and when they were come about halfway between the two houses, the Compl<expan>anan</expan>ts Mother asked this Depon<expan>en</expan>t whether they were goeing, he told her<lb/>
she said she was goeing to live at the Folly on w<expan>hi</expan>ch the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother said come letts go back again and went accordingly And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further says <unclear>the</unclear> Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother had only two Parish Apprentice Girls as her Servants and kept them in so hard a Manner she would Scarce allow <unclear>them</unclear> necessaryes for life <unclear>&amp;</unclear> particular<unclear>ly</unclear> <unclear>xxx them</unclear><lb/>
placed one of the said Apprentice Girls at this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts house onely to lodge there and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath heard the said Girls complain to him and his Wife that her Mistress did allow her little or no Victualls, and that she was almost famisht And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and his Wife hath often given the said Girl Food and Sustenance<lb/>
10.) To the Tenth Interr<expan>ogatorr</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that one day about a Year before the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother dyed she came to this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts house to call him to go with her to beat the hedges and catch Flyes and worms on a Sheet she usually spread for the same, And she had onely one thin Petticoate on, a Pair of <unclear>xxxxxxx</unclear> and no Stockings and <unclear>a</unclear><lb/>
thin Gausehoof so that in this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Judgem<expan>en</expan>t she lookt like a Gipsey and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t went with her from Ten a 'Clock to three and she gave this Depon<expan>en</expan>t One Shilling for his days work, And also sayes that he hath often times seen the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother stand for Three or Four hours together in Tickenham Moore <unclear>with her xxxx</unclear><lb/>
her hand Stirring a Cow turd wherein she said she found a great many Fine Flies, And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further Saith That he was walking one day with one Joseph Barnes in Nailsey Heath and the said Barnes Spied a Cow turd with severall Flies or Worms. in it, which he said he beleived the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts mother would give him<lb/>
a Shilling for it and imiediately tore off a peice of his Shirt tied the said Flyes in it and carried them to the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts mother for which she gave the said Barnes halfe a Crown as he told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t And for these and such like other reasons this Depon<expan>en</expan>t could give he beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was <unclear>not</unclear> of her Sences.<lb/>
17.) To the Seventeenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That he hath heard from and been informed by one Robert Browne that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother sent for the said Brown and ordered him to Breake a Bull so as to make a padd of him fitt for her own rideing or to that effect And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t also saith that she dealt very<lb/>
much and delighted in Butterflies Worms &amp; Flyes and other insects and was at great charge in collecting and gathering them.<lb/>
19.) To the Nineteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That about Six or Seven Years before the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers death in discourse with her <add>hee</add> heard her say That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was none of her Child but that he dyed at Nurse or was there changed and another Child putt in his Roome or to that effect And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
said Madam if Mr Ashfeild is not your own Child Mrs Mary Mrs Eleanor &amp; Mr Richard are and you may settle your Estate on all or one of them and She answered this Depon<expan>en</expan>t she would do with her Estate as She thought best.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Mary Davis Wife of Richard Davis of Tickenham aforesaid Charcoal maker Aged Forty and Eight Yeares or thereabouts Sworne &amp; exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) To the Seventh Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That for Twenty Yeares past and upwards she lived as next Neighbour. toand within half a Mile and a Mile of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother at Tickenham aforesaid and was very well acquainted and often conversant with her and the Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband <unclear>hath rented</unclear><lb/>
severall Estates of her And saith that she the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was reputed and Esteemed by some of her Neighbours in the Country to be a Mad Woman and by others to be besides herself and out of her Sences and in this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Judgem<expan>en</expan>t She was not a Sensible Woman.<lb/>
8.) 9.) To the Eighth and Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not manage her Estate like a Woman in her Sences for she would keep Estates often in her hands and not lett them to Tennants who would rent the same at a reasonable Yearly Value and by her Managem<expan>en</expan>t mak little or <unclear>none</unclear><lb/>
of them, And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lived in a very mean and indifferent manner in her house as to her housekeeping and 'twas kept in a Nasty indecent manner and not like a Woman of her Estate and account and Says also that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not live long in a place but would often<lb/>
remove herself and goods from one House to another and live a little time at Bristoll then at London, and shortly after in the Country again but the reason why She removed so often or go to and fro in that manner this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleives was because she was Maggotty and not in her right Mind and understanding<lb/>
And further sayes that she com<expan>m</expan>only had two Parish Apprentice Girls as her Servants and none elce and did carry herself towards them and her own Children with great cruelty for this Depon<expan>en</expan>t says the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts sister Eleanor and one Mary <unclear>Teague</unclear> One of her Apprentice Girls have told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t that <unclear>the</unclear><lb/>
Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother would oftentimes make them Stripp themselves <unclear>naked</unclear> whether they were in a fault or not and then she would Whipp them <unclear>unm</unclear>ercifully and that once they had tyed up two Ropes in order to hang themselves and had done it if some People had not come accidently to the house about <unclear>thesime</unclear><lb/>
thereby they lost their oppertunity and they told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t the reason of such their intended doeings was on occasioned by the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers hard usage of them And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith she hath asked the said Mary Teague why the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did so she answered that one Bess Knight did use to come and tell the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother <unclear>a</unclear><lb/>
<unclear>parcell</unclear> of Lyes and Shortly after that she would use them in Manner as aforesaid.<lb/>
10.) To the Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That one day about Ten Yeares since the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother came to this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts house Staring and Glowing and looking very wild and in a great passion and bid this Depon<expan>en</expan>t fetch her some drink and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t said Lord Mad<expan>a</expan>m what is the Matter with you and then she fell out laughing <unclear>and</unclear><lb/>
heartily and she would sometimes laugh and cry in one breath and when this Depon<expan>en</expan>t gave her some drink she went away crying againe And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Sayes she hath heard the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother hath done severall Maggotty Tricks and for these and such like reasons she beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was not in her right Sences.<lb/>
(3)<lb/>
<unclear>Ron Shruppe</unclear><lb/>
Sam Fox<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 <unclear>IMG_0507 and IMG_0511</unclear><lb/>
<unclear>verso</unclear> </p>
 <p>
 13.) To the Thirteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y Saith That about four Years and an halfe <unclear>ago by xxxx</unclear>the best of her remembrance This Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband was arrested in the Suite of Edward Gorges and W<expan>illia</expan>m Rogers Esq<expan>ui</expan>re Trustees of and for the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother by the direcc<expan>i</expan>on of the Def<expan>endan</expan>t Thomas Edwards (as the Bayliffe told her said husband)<lb/>
And that sometime after this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband was so arrested <unclear>he went to the</unclear> said Mr Gorges house in Wraxall in the County of Somersett and made complaint to him of his being so arrested who bid this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband to goe to said Mr Edwards and know the meaning of it and why he made use of his name And saith that <unclear>this</unclear><lb/>
Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband went to the said Mrs Edwards accordingly who told him that he knew not the meaneing of it but that he beleived the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was Mad and would be ruled by nobody or to that effect (as this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband told her) And also Saith That shortly after this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband had Spoke with Mr<lb/>
Edwards she and her husband mett the said Mr Gorges told him what the said Mr Edwards had said The said Mr Gorges thereupon seemed to be very angry and said that he did renounce or dissent to Mr Edwards acc<expan>i</expan>ons and that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was worse then the beasts of the Feild for they <unclear>loved</unclear> their <unclear>Young</unclear>.<lb/>
and she did not love any Child she had And that Mr Edwards and Mrs Glanvile were very bad people for that they borrowed a box of writeings of him wherein with other Deeds was a deed of Settlement made by the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother of her Estate on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Father and his Heires and that he was no<unclear>t xxxx</unclear><lb/>
in the said Deed but that Sydenham Beere and Forrest Ashfeild were Trustees therein And that the said Mr Edwards and Mrs Glanvile borrowed the said box of writeings in order to make use of the same at a triall betweene the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother and her husband Mr Glanville And said that<lb/>
they promised to bring the box of writeings back againe to him but had not done it At w<expan>hi</expan>ch he seemed very angry And Saith that she heard the said Mr Gorges also say that he had directed the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t to bring a Bill against his said Mother the Mortgages, and Mr Edwards to discover and p<expan>ro</expan>duce the <unclear>said Deed</unclear><lb/>
of Settlement for to the Very same effect.)<lb/>
31.) To the One and Thirtieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y she saith That she never know or heard that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t or either of his sisters did ever goe to see converse or hold any correspondence with their Mothers husband Mr Glanvile from the time he seperated from her said Mother untill she died.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Henry Cowston of the Parish of Stapleton in the County of Gloucester Coleminer Aged Sixty Two Yeares or thereabouts Sworne and Exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
10.) To the Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That Five Yeares since and <unclear>upwards</unclear> the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother sent to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to come and buy a Wood called Merry feilds Wood of her at Tickenham aforesaid and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t came to her and she sent a man with him to veiw the said Wood and when he had veiwed the same he <unclear>purchased</unclear><lb/>
with the said Man and appointed to come one day the next Week and agree if he could with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother for the said Wood accordingly about a Week after this Depon<expan>en</expan>t came to the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother at the Court house at Tickenham aforesaid and there told that he was come to agree with her about Merry Feilds Wood on <unclear>which</unclear><lb/>
He was shewed into the parlour or Hall where the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was sitting at the Fire by herself, and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t said to her Madam I am come to agree with you if I can about the Wood and repeated those or such like words to her three or Four times in half an hour but the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother made this Depo<expan>onen</expan>t<lb/>
no Answer And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t says he staid in the said Roome two hours or more and repeated often the words he said before but could not gett one Word from the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother. So he arose from his Chaire and went to one Bess Knights who sold Ale in the said Parish as soon as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t came <unclear>unto</unclear><lb/>
the said house Bess King said to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t have Mad<expan>a</expan>m and you agreed about the Wood this Depon<expan>en</expan>t said they had not <unclear>fell ont</unclear> for that he could not gett her to speake one Word on which Bess Knight replyed Mr Ashfeild meaning the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t had taken the Sacrament in order to be a protestant &amp; Mad<expan>a</expan>m<lb/>
meaning the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was Mad about it and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t never troubled himself further about the said Wood And says that for the reasons aforesaid and other things this Depon<expan>en</expan>t hath heard he beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was not alwayes in her right Mind and Senses.<lb/>
13.) To the Thirteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That at the Same time as he went to deale with the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother for the wood as aforesaid he this Depon<expan>en</expan>t discourseing with the said Bess Knight amongst other things the said Knight told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t that she was sent by the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother to Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re <unclear>for a</unclear><lb/>
Deed of Settlement by which as the said Bess Knight told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother had settled all her Estate on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Father and his Heires forever and that the said Mr Gorges gave the said Bess Knight the said Deed of Settlement and she carried the same to the Def<expan>endan</expan>t Mr Edwards and that <unclear>shortly</unclear><lb/>
after she brought the said Deed of Settlement from Mr Edwards and gave it to the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother; which Deed the said Bess Knight also told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t she thought the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother had burnt, for that she never saw or heard of it afterwards.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 John Bryan of Wedmore in the County of Somersett Millwright aged Fifty Yeares and upwards <unclear>p<expan>ro</expan>duced</unclear> Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>eed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followth.<lb/>
7 &amp; 10.) To the Seventh and Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes he saith That about Nine or Tenn Yeares agoe the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lett to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t a Water grist Mill and a Small Estate of hers called Higgins's liveing Scituate in Tickenham in the County of Somersett at Thirty pounds p<expan>er</expan> Ann<expan>um </expan>Rent for Seaven Yeares <unclear>and</unclear><lb/>
promised that the Defend<expan>an</expan>t Mr Thomas Edwards should make this Depon<expan>en</expan>t a lease of it at that Rent and for that Terme and that the Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Wife should manage her affaires in the same manner as one Bess Knight did who then lived in her Neighbourhood That soon after this Depon<expan>e</expan>nt with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t<lb/>
Mothers approbac<expan>i</expan>on entred upon and took possession of the said Mill and all the ground belong to the <add>said</add> liveing but could not gett the poss<expan>ess</expan>ion of the house belonging there to and he afterwards ploughed about three Acres of Feild land part of the ground belonging to the said liveing or Estate and bought<lb/>
timber to repaire the said Mill and at the request of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother took one of her apprentice or parish Girls to assist him or live with him And Saith that he held the said Mill and liveing about half a Yeare and often times desired the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother to grant him such lease but dureing that time she <unclear>was</unclear><lb/>
so very Maggotty and unsettled oftentimes removeing from one house or place to another that he could not bring her to any thing or obtein such lease from her And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t observed that dureing that time she managed her Estate very much to her disadvantage and not like a Woman of discrec<expan>i</expan>on and in her<lb/>
right Sences And Saith That finding that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother would not make him such lease he applyed himself to Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re and S<expan>i</expan>r John Smith two of her Neighbours particular Freinds and acquaintance and informed them thereof who ordered this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to send her Apprentice Maid home and<lb/>
<unclear>three</unclear> up the Mill and liveing into her hands by reason this Depon<expan>en</expan>t could not have his bargaine according to agreem<expan>en</expan>t and for that they beleived she was not compos mentis.<lb/>
13.) To the Thirteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y he saith That some short time before he took the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother Mill and liveing of her aforesaid John Pigot of Brockley in the said County of Somersett Esq<expan>ui</expan>re Employed this Depon<expan>en</expan>t as a Workman to go and buy some Timber of her w<expan>hi</expan>ch he did accordingly and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother<lb/>
then told him that she could not Sell it without the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts consent who was then from home and ordered this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to come another time That he went at the time appointed when the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was at home, And the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t by his Mothers direcc<expan>i</expan>on went with this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to a Wood called MerryFeild<lb/>
in Tickenham aforesaid and Shewed this Depon<expan>en</expan>t the timber but they could not agree about the price.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Richard Jennings of Tickenham in the County of Somersett Husbandman Aged Fifty Years or thereabouts Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) 10.) &amp; 25.) To the Seventh Tenth and Five and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes he saith That he lived for about Sixteene Yeares at Tickenham aforesaid within a Quarter of a Mile of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers house called the Court house and was very well acquainted with her And Saith that She was not reputed by her Neighbours<lb/>
to be a Wise and discreete woman And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleives she was sometimes out of her Sences That about two Yeares before the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother died she sent for this Depon<expan>en</expan>t to her house at Tickenham over Night and he went to her the next morning and when he came she told him she must send him to<lb/>
Bristoll and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t thereupon askt her what was become of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t And told her that he heard he was dead to w<expan>hi</expan>ch she answered she would give this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Five pounds if twas true for then she could sell her Estate which she would do and goe and live in London and never <unclear>come</unclear><lb/>
into the Country againe.<lb/>
22.) To the two and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y he saith That he knows not nor can give any instance of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts his brother and Sisters or either of their disobedience or undutifullness to their Mother nor any Act or Acts of extravagancy that they or either of them was or were Guilty of And Saith that<lb/>
he beleives that they were alwayes very dutifull and obedient to her and he never heard otherwise from the Neighbours.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 William Bennett of the Parish of Tickenham in the County of Somersett Yeoman Aged 61 Yeares or thereabouts p<expan>ro</expan>duced Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) &amp; 8.) to the Seaventh &amp; Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That he lived for Twenty Years past at Tickenham aforesaid near to and in the Neighbourhood of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother and says That she managed her Estate very indiscreetly and not like a Woman in her sences sometimes she would have Tennants and<lb/>
Sometimes none and she would often keep her said Estate in her hands and make little or nothing of it she was once bid six pounds and Tenn Shillings for a Mow of Hay but she would not take under Seven pounds and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t brought the same of John <unclear>Jaeton</unclear> her Servant two Yeares after for Forty shillings<lb/>
and often times when she did lett her said Estate it would be to such poor Fellows as were not able to pay her any Rent.<lb/>
10.) &amp; 22.) To the Tenth and Two and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes This Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That about the Month of March last was two Yeares when the Invasion was intended on Scotland this Depon<expan>en</expan>t had one Day killed a Pigg and made a Pye with some part thereof for his Family, and he and Family dined thereon and <unclear>went</unclear><lb/>
out about their day Labour and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t haveing forgott something went back to his owne house again, and when he came into it he found the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother eating some of the said pye which she called Venison pasty and this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Wife standing by her, this Dep<expan>onen</expan>t spoke to the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother or <unclear>from</unclear><lb/>
to him, and asked one another how they did To w<expan>hi</expan>ch says the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother William Why would not you come &amp; grind at my Mill t'other day when I sent my daughter to you, this Depon<expan>en</expan>t replyed Mad<expan>a</expan>m Sometimes you have a Miller and Sometimes none on which the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother said because you did not<lb/>
come to my Mill when I sent for you, I will begin with my Children first, and they shall suffer and you shall suffer next meaneing as this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleived that when the Prince of Wales came she would cause the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t And his Sister to be murthered and then this Depon<expan>en</expan>t And also sayes that this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts<lb/>
Wife told him this Depon<expan>en</expan>t that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother at that time said that she had one a comeing with a great <unclear>drift</unclear> that would manage her Estate for her, meaneing as this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Wife understood and she She told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t the Prince of Wales, or if he did not come himselfe he would send men enough to take<lb/>
her harvest And also say's that for these and such like words and acc<expan>i</expan>ons this Depon<expan>en</expan>t beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was not alwayes in her senses as other Women are And further Sayes that he this Depon<expan>en</expan>t never knew or heard of any Extravagancy or Acts of disobedience of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts or any<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 <unclear>IMG_0512 and IMG_0513</unclear><lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 of his brothers and sisters towards their said Mother.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Samuel Watts a Witness Sworne and Exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part and now on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) &amp; 22.) To the Seaventh and Two and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that he hath heard from persons at and in the Neighbourhood of Tickenham that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was not a Woman in her right Sences, but this Depon<expan>en</expan>t did not find her so in his dealings w<expan>i</expan>th her about the Wood or otherwise<lb/>
And further Saith That he doth not know or ever heard any extravagancy the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t or his Brothers and Sisters were given to in their lives and <unclear>conncac<expan>i</expan>ons</unclear> nor of any disobedience or undutifullness they or either of them were guilty of towards their said Mother, other than what she hath said to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t And this<lb/>
Depon<expan>en</expan>t say's he hath Sometimes Seen the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his Mother together and hath observed the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t carry himself with duty and respect towards her.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Anne Jones a Witness already Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part and now on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) &amp; 9th.) To the Seventh and Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lived oftentimes in a Year for many Yeares before her death at this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts house in Bristoll And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t observed and took her to be sometimes in her sences and Sometimes out of them And further says<lb/>
that she would often times while she so lived with this Depon<expan>en</expan>t find and provide diet for her self but 'twas very mean and ordinary and not such as was fitt for a woman of her Estate in this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts opinion And sometimes she boarded with this Depon<expan>en</expan>t.<lb/>
10.) To the Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y she Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was Sometimes very unsettled in her Mind and Sometimes would have very odd and Whimsicall acc<expan>i</expan>ons.<lb/>
19.) To the Nineteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y She Saith That Sometime before the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother went last to London she heard her say and declare That she beleived that her Children were none of hers but that they were changed at Nurse And Saith that one Matthew Knight late of Tickenham aforesaid told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
that as he the said Matthew Knight was comeing from Tickenham to Bristoll w<expan>i</expan>th <expan>th</expan>e Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother some short time before she went last to London she said to the said Matthew Knight she was goeing to Bristoll to make her Will and ruin her Children and that she intended to give her Estate to S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodricke and the<lb/>
said Matthew Knight said to the said Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother if Mr Ashfeild meaning the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t had disobliged her the rest of her Children had not and he hoped she would not do such a thing to which she replyed they were not her Children for her Children were changed at Nurse or to that effect, And Saith that the said Matthew<lb/>
Knight is since dead.<lb/>
22.) &amp; 31.) To the Two and Twentieth and One and Thirtieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That she observed the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was dutifull and obedient to his Mother when ever he was at this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts house with or came to see her there, nor doth she know of any undutifullness or extravagancy he was ever guilty towards his said Mother<lb/>
or in his life or Convercac<expan>i</expan>on more than what the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Nor doth she know or ever heard that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t And his sister ever saw went to or corresponded with their Mothers late Husband Mr Glanville nor ever heard that Mr Glanvile came into the Country after He separated from his Wife, or ever<lb/>
attempted to do her any Mischeife other than what the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and she hath sett forth in her Deposic<expan>i</expan>on on <expan>th</expan>e Def<expan>endan</expan>ts part.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Richard Beaker of Weston in Gordon in the County of Somersett Yeoman Aged Six and Forty Yeares or thereabouts being Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
8.) To the Eighth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That he lived for all or the greatest part of his lifetime within two Miles of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers house at Tickenham and was well acquainted with and was related to her And Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother managed great part of her Estate much to her disadvantage and not like<lb/>
a Woman of discrec<expan>i</expan>on in his Opinion for she would often times keep great part of her Estate in her hands and suffer the houses buildings and boundaryes thereof to Run to ruine and much out of Repaire and beleives that sometimes by her ill Management of her Estate she did not make half the Value thereof<lb/>
9.) To the Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y he saith That the pl<expan>aintiff</expan>s Mother did live but very indifferent and meanly in her house and not like a Woman of her Estate for he hath layne at her house oftentimes and sometimes she would leave good meate and drink and sometimes very little and indifferent And saith that she did not continue long in a place but<lb/>
would remove herself and goods from one house of hers to another and from place to place severall times in a Yeare.<lb/>
22.) To the two &amp; Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y he saith That he knows not nor can give any instances of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts or of his brother or either of his sisters disobedience or undutifulnesse to their Mother or any Act or Acts of extravagancy that they or either of them were guilty of and beleives the pl<expan>aintif</expan>f and the rest of her Children behaved themselves<lb/>
very dutifull and obedient to her.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Mary Sherburne of Barton Regis in the County of Glouch<expan>ester</expan> Spinster aged Eighteen Yeares or thereabouts being Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
4.) To the Fourth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That she lived with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother as an Apprentice or Servant from her Childhood and untill she went last for London And Saith that dureing all the time that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived with her, the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t his brother and Sisters alwayes carried and behaved themselves very dutifull<lb/>
respectfull and Obedient to their said Mother but she generally carried herself very Severe and hard towards them for whatever they did for her or by her order would not please her, and she would often refuse to take anything that was Eatable or drinkable from their hands fearing they would poison her.<lb/>
7.) To the Seventh Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That she this Depon<expan>en</expan>t liveing with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother as aforesaid was well acquainted with her and sayes that she was reputed by most of her Neighbours to be a Woman out of her sences, but by some not to be so, but this Depon<expan>en</expan>t says that in her Judgement and opinion she was seldome or never<lb/>
in her right sences.<lb/>
9.) &amp; 10.) To the Ninth and Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not live like a Gentlewoman but in a very mean and ordinary manner in her house as to her house keeping for she seldome kept any drink therein &amp; ne<unclear>v<expan>er</expan></unclear> brewed but once while this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived with her and she also went poor in her Apparell &amp; <add>she</add> kept<lb/>
this Depon<expan>en</expan>t her Children and her other Apprentice Girle And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts mother was alwayes removeing and seldome settled a Fortnight in one place, she would remove herself and goods from house to house and place to place at Midnight, sometimes she would move from the Court house to the Mill<lb/>
thence back again sometimes she would turn out the Miller and be Miller herself, and she would often make this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and her fellow Apprentice be Millers with her, and when she could not sleep at night she would make this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and her other Apprentice Maid who lay in the Chamberwith her Rise at Midnight<lb/>
and wash the said Chamber and other Roomes in the house and keep them up all night long and <del>she</del> send them out by night and day to fetch drink at one Bess Knights and elcewhere And saith that she constantly kept no other Servants but this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and another Apprentice Girle, but she would sometimes have a<lb/>
Man Servant for one quarter of a Year, then turn him off and shortly after take him again and turn him away againe, That she would Sometimes make this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and her fellow Apprentice together, and sometimes <unclear>as under</unclear> stripp themselves Naked &amp; whipp them with an holly stick when ever they did anything amiss<lb/>
and if they cryed out she would hold them by the throat to prevent their makeing a Noise, or beat them till they were quiet and beleives that by such her Usage she was not alwayes in her right mind and sences.<lb/>
20.) To the Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That she beleives the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother loved and valued her Doggs and butterflies more and better than her Children, for that she was well pleased and in good humour when she was amongst her Butterflies but she was uneasye and removeing when her Children were about and in<lb/>
great Fear they would either murther or poison her.<lb/>
22.) &amp; 24.) To the Two and Twentieth and Four and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That she never saw but that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his Sister behaved themselves with duty and obedience to their Mother and alwayes did what she commanded them to do, nor doth this Depon<expan>en</expan>t know or ever hear <add>that</add> the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t was<lb/>
extravagant in his life conversac<expan>i</expan>on or otherwise, And saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother had conceits that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t And her other Children would Murder or poison her, and more perticularly says that she ordered an horse to be bought for her own rideing when he was so bought would not Ride saying her Son the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t<lb/>
had bought him to break her Neck or to that purpose and never Rode on Horseback afterwards to this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts knowledge.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Andrew Parsons of Backwell in the County of Somersett Husbandman Aged Fifty Yeares or thereabouts Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts parte deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
7.) To the Seventh Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That he hath lived at Backwell aforesaid within two Miles of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother for five and Twenty Yeares before her death, and sayes that she was Esteemed and reputed by her Neighbour's in the Country to be a woman Sometimes out of her Sences and not alwayes<lb/>
in her right Mind and understanding, and this Depon<expan>en</expan>t took her to be so.<lb/>
<unclear>IMG_0516 &amp; IMG_0517</unclear><lb/>
19.) &amp; 22.) To the Nineteenth and Two and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That about three Weekes before the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother went last to London she was telling this Depon<expan>en</expan>t that she had a little Estate of about Three pounds and Seventeenth shillings a Yeare <unclear>at Stognsey</unclear> in the County of Somersett out of w<expan>hi</expan>ch she had<lb/>
not rec<expan>eiv</expan>ed one penny for Seventeen Yeares past, she also told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t that she had made nothing out of Rodney Stoke for Twelve Yeares past to w<expan>hi</expan>ch this Depon<expan>en</expan>t replyed if she would give those Estates to her Children they would look after it and make something of it or to that effect, the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother answered<lb/>
that they were none of her Children for her Children were changed at Nurse, And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further saith he knows not nor hath he heard that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t or his brother and Sisters were extravagant in anything or disobedient to their Mother And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t further saith That about a Yeare since or more this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
being in Company with one Mattew Knight &amp; discourseing about the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts mother he the said Matthew Knight told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t he went with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother to Bristoll at the time she made her Will and that as he was walkeing with her she said to him M<unclear>u</unclear>n, meaning the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t do little think what I am goeing to do for<lb/>
I am goeing to make my Will and give my Estate from him and all my Children and that the said Knight replyed Lord Madam I hope you will not do so for if Mr Ashfeild have disobliged you what have Mrs Mary and the Rest of your Children done but the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother said she would do it for that they were<lb/>
none of her Children but were changed at Nurse, and should have none of her Estate or to that effect, And says that the said Matthew Knight dyed ab<expan>ou</expan>t Six Months since.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Elianor Brewton Wife of John Brewton of the Parish of St. James in the County of Glouc<expan>heste</expan>r Yeoman Aged about Fifty Yeares Sworne and Exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts part deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
1st. To the First Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith she knows the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and hath so known him for six Yeares past and upawards but doth not know the Def<expan>endan</expan>t S<expan>i</expan>r Henry Goodrick.<lb/>
3.) To the Third Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother had two Children by her first husband Mr Ashfeild (to witt) the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his sister Mary, she had also two Children by her last husband Mr Glanville (to wit) Eleanor and Richard, but knows not of what age they were respectively in July<lb/>
in the Yeare of our Lord One Thousand Seven hundred and Five But says that in July in the <add>said</add> Yeare One Thousand Seven hundred and Five all the said Children were of the Romish Religion, and so was their Mother And further Saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his Sister Mary now p<expan>ro</expan>fess themselves<lb/>
of the protestant Religion<lb/>
4.) To the Fourth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and <add>his</add> Sisters alwayes behaved themselves with Duty and obedience to their said Mother, but she was very unkind to them, and when she was sick the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his sister Mary came to see her but she refused<lb/>
to see them, And also saith that she maintained them in food and cloathes in a very mean and indifferent manner for she would often borrow Victualls of this Depon<expan>en</expan>t leaveing none of her own And this Depon<expan>en</expan>t never saw or heard of any Educac<expan>i</expan>on the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t gave her said Children.<lb/>
7.) To the Seventh Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That her husband rented an Estate of the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother for three Yeares w<expan>hi</expan>ch expired about two Yeares before her death and while he so rented the said Estate she this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and her husband lived in one part of the house with her as long as she was in the Country and says she was<lb/>
reputed and Esteemed by her Neighbours to be a woman not alwayes in her right understanding, and this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts Judgement was and is so of her.<lb/>
8.) &amp; 9.) To the Eighth and Ninth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did not manage her Estate like a Woman of Discretion, but on the contrary for she would do a thing today and undo it tomorrow she would often times keep her Estates in her hand and not lett them unless she could have an extravagant<lb/>
Rent such as no Tennant could give and thereby she would make but very little advantage of them And also sayes that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother lived in a poor Manner in her house as to housekeeping and beleives many of her Tenants lived much better And further sayth That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother was com<expan>m</expan>only<lb/>
unsettled and often removeing from place to place and house to house, and did not reside long any where, and that she had but two parish Apprentice Girls for her Servants and she used them hard as the said Girls told this Depon<expan>en</expan>t but this Depon<expan>en</expan>t never saw her use them ill And further sayes that She did<lb/>
sometimes keep a Man Servant while she had her Estate in her hand but he did not live longer with her than a Month<lb/>
10.) To the Tenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother did two or three times rise at Midnight and come into this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts and her husbands roome saying she was afraid of Theives and of being Murthered by the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his Companions, and she would cause this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts husband to rise and<lb/>
look out, and she would cry and be outraged for fear she should be killed And further sayes that once while this Depon<expan>en</expan>t lived in the house with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother, she invited this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and her husband to dine with her, and they came accordingly and when they were at Dinner the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother said she was<lb/>
newly married to her son and that that was her wedding day and she called her son the Brideman and told him he should waite at the table that day and she would waite tomorrow or to that effect and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t did waite at the table give drink and other things to his Mother this Depon<expan>en</expan>t and her Husband and they were<lb/>
all very merry and the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t and his Mother good freinds but in a little time she fell out with him And her acc<expan>i</expan>ons did bespeak her that was not a Woman in her right Mind and Sences as other women were.<lb/>
17.) &amp; 20.) To the Seventeenth and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>yes this Depon<expan>en</expan>t Saith That the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother dealt much in Butterflyes flyes Worms and other insects and she and her two Apprentice Girls and others spent a great deale of time and she was at a great deale of charge in collecting them, And further sayes that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
beleives by her behaviour towards her children, she Valued her Doggs and Butterflies more than them.<lb/>
31.) To the One and Thirtieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y she saith That she never knew or heard that the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t or his sisters or either of them did ever goe to see converse or correspond w<expan>i</expan>th Mr. Richard Glanvile the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mothers husband from the time he seperated from her till her death And never heard that the said Mr.<lb/>
Glanvile ever came into the Country where the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother dwelt after the time of his seperac<expan>i</expan>on from her or ever attempted to take away her life or doe her any Mischeife.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Mary Page Wife of W<expan>illia</expan>m Page of Backwell in the County of Somersett Yeoman aged Fifty Yeares and upwards being Sworne and Examined deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
19.) To the Nineteenth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith That she Heard one Matthew Knight late of Tickenham in the County of Somersett lately dec<expan>eas</expan>ed say that he went with the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother to Bristoll and in his way thither the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother said that she beleived Mun, meaning the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>t did little think what she was goeing<lb/>
to doe For she was goeing to Bristoll to Mr Edwards to make her Will and intended to give away her Estate from him And that he the said Matthew Knight thereupon said God forbid you should do any such thing I hope God will turn your heart before you come there, Why can't you and your Children agree as well as other<lb/>
Children and their parents to w<expan>hi</expan>ch the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother replyed they are none of my Children <del>to</del> <add>the</add> Nurse changed them and kept my children and gave me Changelins for them or to that effect.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Francis Irish of Ashton in the County of Somersett Spinster Aged Five and Forty Yeares or thereabouts Sworne and exa<expan>m</expan>i<expan>n</expan>ed deposeth as followeth.<lb/>
23.) To the three and Twentieth Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y this Depon<expan>en</expan>t saith that she verily beleives she did see Elianor Glanvile the Compl<expan>ainan</expan>ts Mother and Edward Gorges Esq<expan>ui</expan>re signe seale and Deliver as her Act and Deed the parchment writeing now p<expan>ro</expan>duced to this Depon<expan>en</expan>t at this the time of her Examinac<expan>i</expan>on for that this Depon<expan>en</expan>t<lb/>
finds her name thereto sett as a Witness to the sealing and delivery thereof And Saith that the name Francies Irish so there to subscribed as a Witness is of this Depon<expan>en</expan>ts own p<expan>ro</expan>per handwriteing And more to this Interr<expan>ogator</expan>y Saith not.<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 Row<expan>land</expan> Thrupp<lb/>
Sam<expan>ue</expan>ll Fox<lb/>
</p>
 <p>
 4)<lb/>


</p></div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>